{
    "pairs": [
        {
            "question": "“A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm.” Which of Isaac Asimov’s Three Laws of Robotics is this?",
            "answer": "First law"
        },
        {
            "question": "“Know thyself” was a widely-known aphorism of which country?",
            "answer": "Ancient Greece"
        },
        {
            "question": "“Last of the Romans” is an epithet used to describe someone with a classical Roman way of thinking. Who could NOT exemplify that?",
            "answer": "Attila"
        },
        {
            "question": "“Machu Picchu” is a notable relic of which civilization?",
            "answer": "The Incas"
        },
        {
            "question": "“Man of Peace” is the nickname of which commander?",
            "answer": "Imhotep"
        },
        {
            "question": "“One hundred forty thousand all disarmed! Among these was there not a single man?” Which Tang-dynasty poet wrote this couplet?",
            "answer": "Madame Huarui"
        },
        {
            "question": "“Ophelia” is a character in which of these works?",
            "answer": "Hamlet"
        },
        {
            "question": "“Puncture Wounds” is the skill of which character in Ceroli Crisis?",
            "answer": "Astrid"
        },
        {
            "question": "“Ru ware” is one of the most famous types of Chinese pottery, known for its delicate pale blue glaze. Which dynasty did it originate from?",
            "answer": "Song"
        },
        {
            "question": "“The end justifies the means” was a key belief of the author of “The Prince”. What was his name?",
            "answer": "Machiavelli"
        },
        {
            "question": "“Tongwancheng” was the capital of which ethnic group from ancient China?",
            "answer": "The Xiongnu"
        },
        {
            "question": "A crater on the far side of the Moon is named after a Chinese official who was (supposedly) the first person to travel into space. What was his name?",
            "answer": "Wan Hu"
        },
        {
            "question": "A decrease in which of the following metrics might indicate increasing nearness to a state of vacuum?",
            "answer": "Air pressure"
        },
        {
            "question": "A human fingernail is made of which material?",
            "answer": "Alpha-keratin"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to Chinese legend, which of the following is not one of the weaknesses of the fearsome beast known as the “Nian”?",
            "answer": "Water"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to Greek mythology, which two gods transformed into the “fish” in the symbol of Pisces?",
            "answer": "Aphrodite and Eros"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to Maya chronology, the Late Late Preclassic Period falls within:",
            "answer": "1 BCE to 159 CE"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to the tale of the She-wolf in Roman mythology, what came of the twins she nurtured, Romulus and Remus?",
            "answer": "Romulus became the founder and first King of Rome"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to World Athletics, which of these is NOT an official international discus weight?",
            "answer": "1.25kg"
        },
        {
            "question": "Acquiring Commander William I unlocks which of these achievements?",
            "answer": "Path of Glory"
        },
        {
            "question": "Advantages of Johannes Gutenberg’s printing press include all of the following except what?",
            "answer": "Increase in church power"
        },
        {
            "question": "After a Venus Flytrap catches an insect, how does it digest and absorb the prey?",
            "answer": "The inner flaps of the leaves secrete a digestive fluid"
        },
        {
            "question": "After its foundation in the 6th century BCE, which institution of the Roman Republic served as a consultative parliament?",
            "answer": "The Senate"
        },
        {
            "question": "After the Lost Kingdom opens, what item do you have to spend to teleport to and from the Lost Kingdom?",
            "answer": "Random Teleport"
        },
        {
            "question": "After the students at the Lyceum of Wisdom finish their lessons, what building in your city do they return to?",
            "answer": "Academy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Afterglow is caused by:",
            "answer": "Light scattering in air"
        },
        {
            "question": "Alliance help can NOT speed up which of the following activities?",
            "answer": "Troop training"
        },
        {
            "question": "Amethyst is valued for its brilliant violet hue. What mineral is it a variety of?",
            "answer": "Quartz"
        },
        {
            "question": "Apart from “Number of Scouts” and “Power”, which of the following Scout Camp parameters can also be upgraded?",
            "answer": "Scout March Speed and Exploration Range"
        },
        {
            "question": "Apart from “Times You Can Be Helped” and “Power”, which of the following Alliance Center parameters can also be upgraded?",
            "answer": "Reinforcement Troop Capacity"
        },
        {
            "question": "As of 2024, which of these buildings has NOT been fully built?",
            "answer": "Sagrada Família"
        },
        {
            "question": "As of the 2018 World Cup, how many times has Shakira performed at the World Cup closing ceremony?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "As of the 2018 World Cup, how many World Cups has Brazil won?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "As of the 2018 World Cup, what is the United State’s best ever World Cup result?",
            "answer": "Third place"
        },
        {
            "question": "As of the 2018 World Cup, which player holds the record for most goals scored in a single World Cup match with five goals?",
            "answer": "Oleg Salenko"
        },
        {
            "question": "As of the 2018 World Cup, who holds the record for most goals scored in the World Cup?",
            "answer": "Miroslav Klose"
        },
        {
            "question": "As of the 2018 World Cup, who holds the World Cup record for fastest goal scored at 11 seconds?",
            "answer": "Hakan Şükür"
        },
        {
            "question": "As of the 2022 World Cup, how many countries have won the World Cup?",
            "answer": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "As of the 21st World Cup, who is the only player to have scored a hat-trick in 2 different World Cups?",
            "answer": "Gabriel Batistuta"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ashoka the Great was the King of which Ancient Indian kingdom?",
            "answer": "Maurya"
        },
        {
            "question": "Assuming the absence of any other special buffs, which of these commanders has the highest march speed?",
            "answer": "Belisarius"
        },
        {
            "question": "At what level does the Trading Posts transport tax rate become 10%?",
            "answer": "24"
        },
        {
            "question": "At what VIP level can you purchase a VIP Special chest that contains enough Hannibal Barca sculptures to awaken him?",
            "answer": "14"
        },
        {
            "question": "At which VIP level do you permanently unlock a second building queue?",
            "answer": "Lvl. 6"
        },
        {
            "question": "Bhutan is also known as the Land of the Thunder Dragon. What is its capital and largest city?",
            "answer": "Thimphu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Big Ben is located in which of the following countries?",
            "answer": "United Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Black Forest Cake is a famous European dessert. In which country is the Black Forest from which it takes its name?",
            "answer": "Germany"
        },
        {
            "question": "Bossa nova is a popular genre of music originating from which country?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Broccoli is rich in which vitamin?",
            "answer": "Vitamin C"
        },
        {
            "question": "By what other name are Ceroli Chieftains Ak & Hok also known by?",
            "answer": "The Astral Twins"
        },
        {
            "question": "By what other name is October also known under Japan’s old calendar?",
            "answer": "Kannazuki"
        },
        {
            "question": "By what other name is the Ceroli Chieftain Wafura also known?",
            "answer": "Wolfshadow"
        },
        {
            "question": "Cactus spines are actually a modified form of which other part of the plant?",
            "answer": "Leaves"
        },
        {
            "question": "Champagne is a region in which country?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Charles Macintosh crafted a very early version of a raincoat from which material?",
            "answer": "Rubber"
        },
        {
            "question": "China’s “crosstalk” sketch comedy format originates in three places: Tianqiao in Beijing, the Quanye Bazaar in Tianjin, and where in Nanjing?",
            "answer": "Fuzimiao"
        },
        {
            "question": "Combat Tactics is an important Military Technology – what effect does it have?",
            "answer": "Increases Attack of all units"
        },
        {
            "question": "Commander Björn Ironside’s “Viking Lord” skill benefits which of the following unit types?",
            "answer": "Infantry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Darwin’s last book primarily discussed which species’ influence on soil?",
            "answer": "Earthworms"
        },
        {
            "question": "Diego Velázquez, the painter of the realist work Portrait of Pope Innocent X, was from which country?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "During a solar eclipse, the celestial object that comes between the Sun and the Earth is:",
            "answer": "The Moon"
        },
        {
            "question": "During China’s Warring States Period, which state defeated the other six and built the unified Chinese empire?",
            "answer": "Qin"
        },
        {
            "question": "During nuclear fusion, which of the following elements produces less energy than it absorbs?",
            "answer": "Iron"
        },
        {
            "question": "During the Renaissance, why was Florence significant?",
            "answer": "Birthplace and symbol of the Renaissance"
        },
        {
            "question": "During the Second Punic War, in which battle did a vastly outnumbered Hannibal defeat a Roman army?",
            "answer": "The Battle of Cannae"
        },
        {
            "question": "During the Trojan War, which Greek warrior killed Hector?",
            "answer": "Achilles"
        },
        {
            "question": "During the Upper and Lower Egypt period, what color was the crown of the pharaoh of Upper Egypt?",
            "answer": "White"
        },
        {
            "question": "During which Chinese dynasty was the Siku Quanshu compiled?",
            "answer": "Qing"
        },
        {
            "question": "During which emperor’s reign was the Roman Colosseum completed?",
            "answer": "Titus"
        },
        {
            "question": "During which season are nights relatively short and days relatively long?",
            "answer": "Summer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Edward VIII became King of England in January 1936. Later in the same year, in which month did he give up the throne?",
            "answer": "December"
        },
        {
            "question": "Egyptians made paper from which material?",
            "answer": "Papyrus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Egypt’s economy was primarily based on what?",
            "answer": "Agriculture"
        },
        {
            "question": "Elbe Day was the meeting of which two armies during World War II?",
            "answer": "USA, USSR"
        },
        {
            "question": "Equipment with special talent bonuses will have their attributes enhanced by what percentage when equipped to a commander with the corresponding talent?",
            "answer": "30%"
        },
        {
            "question": "Feijoada is considered a national dish of which country?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "First created in Ancient Greece, to which profession does the Hippocratic Oath apply?",
            "answer": "Doctors"
        },
        {
            "question": "Fish and chips has its earliest origins in which country?",
            "answer": "England"
        },
        {
            "question": "Focaccia is a type of pizza-like bread. Which country (and its cooking culture) created the focaccia?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Foie gras is a very nutrient-rich food. Which country produces the most foie gras?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "For every 1 unit you train in your city, how many expedition units do you get in Expedition mode?",
            "answer": "1"
        },
        {
            "question": "For how many francs did Charles V ransom Bertrand du Guesclin during the conflict over Brittany?",
            "answer": "100,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "For which disease did Edward Jenner, known as the father of immunology, develop a vaccine?",
            "answer": "Smallpox"
        },
        {
            "question": "France and Germany were both once part of what feudal Kingdom?",
            "answer": "Francia"
        },
        {
            "question": "French National Day is on July 14 in order to coincide with which historical event?",
            "answer": "Storming of the Bastille"
        },
        {
            "question": "From the 17th to 19th centuries, the Kingdom of Prussia was mostly in which modern country?",
            "answer": "Germany"
        },
        {
            "question": "From the 8th to the 11th century CE, what did Europeans frequently call the Scandinavian invaders who frequently ravaged their lands?",
            "answer": "Vikings"
        },
        {
            "question": "Galileo’s Leaning Tower of Pisa experiment overturned a theory of which Ancient Greek scientist?",
            "answer": "Aristotle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Global warming will NOT lead to:",
            "answer": "A drop in sea levels"
        },
        {
            "question": "Governors cannot earn Activity Points through which of the following?",
            "answer": "Expeditions"
        },
        {
            "question": "Halley’s Comet can be observed from Earth every…",
            "answer": "75-76 years"
        },
        {
            "question": "Held in 1929, how long did the first Academy Awards (“Oscars”) ceremony take?",
            "answer": "15 minutes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Hieroglyphs were part of which country’s formal writing system?",
            "answer": "Ancient Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Homer’s epic “The Iliad” focuses on events happening during which war or battle?",
            "answer": "The Trojan War"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you get Alliance Technology Credits?",
            "answer": "By donating to research Alliance Technology"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you get Alliance Technology Points?",
            "answer": "By donating to research Alliance Technology"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do you obtain the Friend of the Kingdom achievement?",
            "answer": "Visit 100 tribal villages"
        },
        {
            "question": "How high in the Sunset Canyon daily ranking do you need to place before you can receive the Golden Key Daily Rewards?",
            "answer": "In the top 5"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long did the Hundred Years’ War between England and France last?",
            "answer": "116 years"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long does it take for the Earth to complete one revolution around the Sun?",
            "answer": "1 year"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long does the “Basic Army Expansion” boost last?",
            "answer": "4h"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long does the rune dropped by defeating the Guardians remain on the map?",
            "answer": "8 hours"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long would it take for a beam of light to circle the earth 7 times?",
            "answer": "0.94 seconds"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many “Golden Kingdom Equipment Troves” are contained within the Golden Chest earned from stage 16 of the “Golden Kingdom” event?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many arrows are stuck in the shield of commander Lohar?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many beasts can you expect to see fighting alongside Lvl 20 barbarian troops in Rise of Kingdoms",
            "answer": "1 bear and 2 wolves"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many bones does an adult human normally have?",
            "answer": "206"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many bowmen are shown practising in the Archery Range when training composite bowmen?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many cards in total are shown in the Mysterious Merchant’s hands?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many daily Activity Points do you need in “Lucerne Scrolls” to claim the Daily Gift clue reward?",
            "answer": "50"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many days are in a leap year?",
            "answer": "366 days"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many dispatches do you need to complete at the State Forum to open a Dispatch Commendation?",
            "answer": "15"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Easter eggs are featured in the Easter Egg Avatar Frame?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many emeralds are featured on the clothing of commander Matilda of Flanders?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many flags are featured in front of the Alliance Center for the French civilization?",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many gears are shown on the icon for the Economic Technology “Engineering”?",
            "answer": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many goals does a player need to score to earn a hat-trick?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Golden Keys are awarded to the top finishing Governor in each season of Sunset Canyon?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many humans have walked on the Moon?",
            "answer": "12"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many hurricanes were recorded around the Pacific Ocean in the year 1977?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many individual credits can be earned from selling normal equipment blueprints through the Alliance Shop’s reclaim feature?",
            "answer": "400"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many individual quests does an Expedition involve?",
            "answer": "90"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many items of the same quality should I equip to complete “Ready For Battle”?",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Key Points are required to unlock the Treasure of Blue Crystal in Alliance Gifts?",
            "answer": "3,000,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many keys are included in the Alliance Gift received for the destruction of a Lvl 5 Barbarian Fort?",
            "answer": "60"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many keys are included in the Wooden Chest Alliance Gift?",
            "answer": "10"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many keys does a typical modern piano have?",
            "answer": "88"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Legendary Commander Sculptures are awarded to the top finisher by total rankings in the “The Mightiest Governor” event?",
            "answer": "180"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many letters are used in today’s version of English?",
            "answer": "26"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Medals of the Conqueror are needed to purchase a Legendary Commander Sculpture in the Medal Store in Expedition mode?",
            "answer": "1,500"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many minutes’ worth total of speedups can be obtained from purchasing the “7-Day Speedup Supply” in addition to the immediate 1,050 Gem reward?",
            "answer": "3,150 minutes"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many moons does the dwarf planet Quaoar have?",
            "answer": "1"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Normal Iron Ore do you need to make an Advanced Iron Ore?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many officers (excluding the alliance leader) can an alliance have?",
            "answer": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Olympic gold medals did African-American athlete Jesse Owens win in 1936?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many patrolling soldiers roam a governor’s walls?",
            "answer": "7"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many phases are there in The Mightiest Governor event?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many players are there in the board game Go?",
            "answer": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many points are earned per 1 point of upgraded Power within the “Stage 4: Power Upgrade” segment of “The Mightiest Governor” event?",
            "answer": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many points are gained per Lvl 3 unit severely wounded/killed in the “Stage 5: Enemy Elimination” segment of the “Mightiest Governor” event?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many polar bears feature on the Heart of the North Avatar Frame?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many refreshes are available per visit to the Mysterious Merchant?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many reward chests are awarded for reaching 60 daily activity points?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many roses feature on the Rose Petals Avatar Frame?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Scouts can the Scout Camp hold at once?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many sections are featured in the Kingdom Newspaper outside of special calendar events?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many separate khanates or empires had the Mongol Empire fractured into by the time of Kublai’s death in 1294?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many small tents can you see in a Lvl 3 Barbarian Fort?",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many stars are featured on the banner displayed behind the commander Minamoto no Yoshitsune?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many students sit in on the lectures held by the scholars of the Lyceum of Wisdom?",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many teams competed in the 2022 World Cup?",
            "answer": "32"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many teams took part in the first World Cup?",
            "answer": "13"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many tents are shown on the icon for the Military Technology “Encampment”?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many tiles does a City Hall occupy within your city?",
            "answer": "9 x 9"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many times can you receive alliance help if your Alliance Center is level 14?",
            "answer": "18"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many times can you receive alliance help if your alliance center is level 25?",
            "answer": "30"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many times has North Korea qualified for the World Cup?",
            "answer": "Two times"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many times is the character “1” used when you write from number 1 to number 99?",
            "answer": "20"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many troops are recommended for destroying a Lvl 3 Barbarian Fort?",
            "answer": "480,000 Lvl 3 units"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many troops can governors send with a level 17 City Hall or above?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many VIP points can you buy with 200 gems?",
            "answer": "200"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Watchtowers are included in a Lvl 25 city?",
            "answer": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many wheels are there on a battering ram?",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Women’s World Cups has Megan Rapinoe won?",
            "answer": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many World Cup titles has Italy won?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many World Cup titles has Pelé won?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many years are there between each Winter Olympic Games?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much capacity does a Lvl 15 Hospital provide (excluding boosts)?",
            "answer": "29,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much does the 12-Hour Enhanced Attack item increase your troops’ Attack by?",
            "answer": "5%"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much experience does a commander earn from a Lvl 7 Tome of Knowledge?",
            "answer": "50,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much gold does a single issue of the Kingdom Newspaper cost?",
            "answer": "1,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much reinforcement troop capacity does a city receive at Alliance Center Lvl 20?",
            "answer": "575,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much stone will a Lvl 17 Quarry produce every hour (excluding boosts)?",
            "answer": "2,775"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much total daily contribution is required to place in the daily alliance contribution rankings?",
            "answer": "10,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much will an Enhanced Attack (Advanced) item increase your attack?",
            "answer": "10%"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much will an Enhanced Gathering item increase your gathering speed?",
            "answer": "50%"
        },
        {
            "question": "How often does the World Cup take place?",
            "answer": "Every 4 years"
        },
        {
            "question": "How often is the FIFA World Cup held?",
            "answer": "Every 4 years"
        },
        {
            "question": "How was the Gutenberg Bible put into mass production?",
            "answer": "Movable type printing press"
        },
        {
            "question": "If a man with type AB blood and a woman with type B blood have a baby, which of the following statements would be incorrect?",
            "answer": "It could have type O blood"
        },
        {
            "question": "Iguazu Falls lies on the border of which two countries?",
            "answer": "Brazil and Argentina"
        },
        {
            "question": "In “Republic”, what does Plato identify as the “highest form”?",
            "answer": "Form of the Good"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 1582, Oda Nobunaga was betrayed and ambushed by his general Akechi Mitsuhide. Where did this occur?",
            "answer": "Honnō-ji Temple in Kyoto"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 1689, which two rulers granted royal assent to the English Bill of Rights?",
            "answer": "William III and Mary II"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 1970, an Apollo mission attempted to land on the moon. Due to a technical issue, it only managed to orbit around the moon and return to Earth. What was the name of the mission?",
            "answer": "Apollo 13"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 1970, which goalkeeper made the “save of the century” against Pelé?",
            "answer": "Gordon Banks"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 2002, FIFA published a fan-selected World Cup Dream Team. Who was the goalkeeper?",
            "answer": "Lev Yashin"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 2010, at age 71, Otto Rehhagel became the oldest person to manage a World Cup team. Which team did he manage?",
            "answer": "Greece"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 2018, which country set the record for being the least-populated country to ever reach the World Cup?",
            "answer": "Iceland"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 2026, the US, Mexico, and Canada will co-host the World Cup. How many teams will be participating?",
            "answer": "48"
        },
        {
            "question": "In a human body, which of the following bones is closest to the heart?",
            "answer": "Sternum"
        },
        {
            "question": "In aerodynamics, what is it called when the airflow around an object is near or slightly above the speed of sound (around Mach 0.8-1.2)?",
            "answer": "Transonic flow"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ancient Egypt, which of the following was NOT a privilege of being a ‘Scribe’?",
            "answer": "Exempt from paying medical expenses if sick"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ancient Greece, the Delian League was led by which city-state?",
            "answer": "Athens"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ancient Greece, which philosopher liked to discuss ideas on a street which then got the nickname “Peripatetic School”?",
            "answer": "Aristotle"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ancient Greece, who was the high priestess of the Temple of Apollo at Delphi?",
            "answer": "The Pythia"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ancient Greek mythology, who was Hermes’ father?",
            "answer": "Zeus"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ancient Greek mythology, who was the wife of Hades, the king of the underworld?",
            "answer": "Persephone"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ark of Osiris, how many teleports does the first alliance to occupy an obelisk earn?",
            "answer": "8"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ark of Osiris, what effect does the Desert Storm skill have on enemy troops?",
            "answer": "Deals skill damage"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ark of Osiris, what is the requirement for an alliance to participate in the Golden Battlefield?",
            "answer": "Ranked top 20 for alliance power in their kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ark of Osiris, which Speedup can you use?",
            "answer": "Healing Speedup"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ark of Osiris, where are you supposed to take the Ark?",
            "answer": "A non-enemy building"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Æthelflæd’s RoK story, she mentions that she “smells demons”. Who are the “demons” she’s referring to?",
            "answer": "Vikings"
        },
        {
            "question": "In China’s Han Dynasty, who opened the Silk Road on the orders of Emperor Wu?",
            "answer": "Zhang Qian"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Chinese mythology, what kind of creature is Jingwei?",
            "answer": "A bird"
        },
        {
            "question": "In DC comics, what is Batman’s real name?",
            "answer": "Bruce Wayne"
        },
        {
            "question": "In French novelist Stendhal’s The Red and the Black, what is the name of the ambitious protagonist?",
            "answer": "Julien"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Golden Kingdom, how many passes do you need to clear to get a Golden Chest?",
            "answer": "4 Passes"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, to whom did Paris, the Prince of Troy, give a golden apple inscribed with, “To the most beautiful goddess”?",
            "answer": "Aphrodite"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, what is the Goddess Eos known as?",
            "answer": "Goddess of the Dawn"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, what is the relationship between Zeus and Hermes?",
            "answer": "Father and son"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, what was Achilles’ only weak point?",
            "answer": "His heels"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, what was the name of Hades’ 3-headed dog which guarded the gates of the Underworld?",
            "answer": "Cerberus"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, what was the name of the king who turned everything he tuoched into gold?",
            "answer": "Midas"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, which hero quested for the Golden Fleece?",
            "answer": "Jason"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, which hero rode the flying horse Pegasus?",
            "answer": "Bellerophon"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, who is the hero known for stealing fire from the gods and giving it to humankind?",
            "answer": "Prometheus"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, who ran the chariot of the sun off its path, setting the earth aflame?",
            "answer": "Phaethon"
        },
        {
            "question": "In her in-game dialogue, who does Cleopatra VII mention was assassinated by his own senators?",
            "answer": "Julius Caesar"
        },
        {
            "question": "In her RoK story, Æthelflæd mentions the gem in her crown. Who gave her the gem?",
            "answer": "Her father"
        },
        {
            "question": "In his in-game dialogue, which commander does Sun Tzu warn the governor to keep an eye on?",
            "answer": "Cao Cao"
        },
        {
            "question": "In his in-game dialogue, who does Lohar say is the “cruelest man” he’s ever met?",
            "answer": "High Chieftain Gavar"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Homer’s epic “The Iliad”, which of theh following goddesses was NOT part of the competition for the Golden Apple?",
            "answer": "Artemis"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Japan, “torii” gates are usually placed at the entrance of what buildings?",
            "answer": "Shrines"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Japan, which fruit is known as the “fruit of immortality”?",
            "answer": "Tachibana"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Maya mythology, how many levels are there in the heavens and the underworld combined?",
            "answer": "22"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Morse code, what is the length in dots between two words?",
            "answer": "7 dots"
        },
        {
            "question": "In most cases, which kind of lion has a mane?",
            "answer": "Adult male"
        },
        {
            "question": "In mythology, who was hit by the lead arrow of Eros?",
            "answer": "Daphne"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Norse mythology, the ravens Huginn and Muninn were the companions of which god?",
            "answer": "Odin"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Norse mythology, what variety of trees was the World Tree?",
            "answer": "Ash"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Norse mythology, who does the hammer Mjolnir belong to?",
            "answer": "Thor"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Norse mythology, who wielded the weapon Gungnir?",
            "answer": "Odin"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK’s Golden Kingdom of Karaku, gold is believed to be a gift from which god?",
            "answer": "The Sun Above"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, how many soldiers stand in front of the gates of your city?",
            "answer": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, the Cataphract is which civilization’s special unit?",
            "answer": "Byzantium"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, the Hwarang is which civilization’s special unit?",
            "answer": "Korea"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, the Janissary is which civilization’s special unit?",
            "answer": "Ottoman Empire"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, the Throwing Axeman is which civilization’s special unit?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, there is a road paved with golden bricks that can be purchased for 100 Gems. What is it called?",
            "answer": "King’s Road"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, what crops are grown on your city’s Farms?",
            "answer": "Corn"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, what do you have to do to complete the quest “Sword of the King”?",
            "answer": "Recruit 200 infantry units"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, what is the maximum number of Goldmines a player can build?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, what is the nickname of the commander Constance?",
            "answer": "Queen of Sicily"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, what level Scout Camp do you need to dispatch 3 scouts at once?",
            "answer": "Lvl 11"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which building can you use to view your kingdom’s history?",
            "answer": "Monument"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which commander can dispel enemy Attack buffs?",
            "answer": "Amanitore"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which commander has the nickname “Queen of Sicily”?",
            "answer": "Constance"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which commander has the nickname “Žižka of the Chalice”?",
            "answer": "Jan Žižka"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which commander has the skill “Beauty and Wisdom”?",
            "answer": "Cleopatra VII"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which commander has the title “Beloved of Thoth”?",
            "answer": "Thutmose III"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which commander is nicknamed “Queen of Silla”?",
            "answer": "Seondeok"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which Kingdom Chronicles chapter requires all fog in your kingdom to be fully explored?",
            "answer": "Long Peace"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of Sun Tzu’s skills is enhanced by his expertise skill?",
            "answer": "Art of War"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of the following armaments can be used with the arch formation?",
            "answer": "Emblem of the North"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of the following CANNOT increase the Health of your infantry units?",
            "answer": "Trading Post level"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of the following characters does Sun Tzu mention in his Trust dialogue?",
            "answer": "Mulan"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of the following commanders carries a shield?",
            "answer": "Hermann"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of the following commanders excels at leading siege units?",
            "answer": "Margaret I"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of the following decorations has to be purchased with Gems?",
            "answer": "Vase"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of the following is considered a Boost item?",
            "answer": "Peace Shield"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of the following is NOT one of Mulan’s skills?",
            "answer": "Clever Heart"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, which of these commanders is NOT good at leading archer units?",
            "answer": "Saladin"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Roman mythology, which animal is the goddess Minerva often associated with?",
            "answer": "Owl"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Russian history, what nickname was the first Tzar given for their tyranny?",
            "answer": "Ivan the Terrible"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Shakespeare’s Macbeth, the titular character murders King Duncan of Scotland. What is the name of Duncan’s eldest son?",
            "answer": "Malcolm"
        },
        {
            "question": "In soccer, which position is allowed to touch the ball with their hands while it is in their team’s penalty area?",
            "answer": "Goalkeeper"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Sunset Canyon, how many troops can you deploy at a time?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the “Batman” series by DC Comics, which iteration of Robin died as a result of a reader vote?",
            "answer": "Jason Todd (Red Hood)"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the “Gather Resources” stage of the Mightiest Governor event, how many points do you get for gathering 1 gem?",
            "answer": "150"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 16th-17th centuries, which disease did the famous bird-masked “plague doctors” treat?",
            "answer": "Bubonic plague"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 1966 World Cup, England manager Alf Ramsey began using a unique formation that led England to the World Cup title. What was notable about this formation?",
            "answer": "No wingers"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2006 World Cup, Switzerland did not concede a single goal in regular play. Who was their goalkeeper?",
            "answer": "Pascal Zuberbühler"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2006 World Cup, who was the only English player to score during penalties in England’s quarter-final match against Portugal?",
            "answer": "Owen Hargreaves"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2010 World Cup Final between Spain and the Netherlands, which Spanish player scored the game-winning goal?",
            "answer": "Andrés Iniesta"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2010 World Cup, which goalkeeper saved two penalty kicks during regular play?",
            "answer": "Brad Friedel"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2014 World Cup Final between Germany and Argentina, which German player scored the game-winning goal?",
            "answer": "Mario Götze"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2014 World Cup held in Brazil, how many cities held match venues?",
            "answer": "12"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2014 World Cup held in Brazil, how many Confederation of African Football teams qualified for the tournament?",
            "answer": "5"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2014 World Cup, which of the following teams was not in the same group as the eventual champions Germany?",
            "answer": "England"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2018 World Cup, Thibaut Courtois won the Golden Glove award for best goalkeeper. What country is he from?",
            "answer": "Belgium"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2018 World Cup, what other countries were in England’s Group G?",
            "answer": "Belgium, Panama, Tunisia"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2018 World Cup, which of the following teams was not in the same group as the eventual champions France?",
            "answer": "Germany"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2022 World Cup, how many teams made it through the group stage to the knockout stage?",
            "answer": "16"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2022 World Cup, which two teams stayed in university accommodations?",
            "answer": "Argentina, Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2022 World Cup, who faced the host country Qatar in the opening match?",
            "answer": "Ecuador"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2022 World Cup, who was the first team to be eliminated?",
            "answer": "Qatar"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 49 BCE Roman civil war, who was Julius Caesar’s primary opponent?",
            "answer": "Gnaeus Pompeius Magnus"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Book of Exodus, who leads the Jewish people to the Promised Land?",
            "answer": "Moses"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Chinese folklore story “The Cowherd and the Weaver Girl”, which constellation does the cowherd represent?",
            "answer": "Aquila"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the COMMANDER VIEW page, what buff do commanders acting as a “Bloodfist Guard” get?",
            "answer": "Troop Health +1%"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the COMMANDER VIEW page, what buff do commanders acting as a “Drillmaster” get?",
            "answer": "Troop Attack +1%"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the COMMANDER VIEW page, what buff do commanders acting as a “Iron Guard” get?",
            "answer": "Troop Health +1%"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the COMMANDER VIEW page, what buff do commanders acting as a “Ranger” get?",
            "answer": "None of these answers are correct"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the COMMANDER VIEW page, what buff do commanders acting as a “Tax Officer” get?",
            "answer": "Gathering Speed +5%"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the competition for the Golden Boot, if two players have scored the same number of goals, how is the winner determined?",
            "answer": "Assists"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Desire of Victory event, how can players gain rewards?",
            "answer": "Training troops"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Emerald Tablet, Hermes Trismegistus claims to hold “three parts of the wisdom of the whole world”. Which of these is NOT one of the three parts?",
            "answer": "Transfiguration"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Grimms’ fairy tale “Town Musicians of Bremen”, a group of animals travels to Bremen together to become musicians. Which of the following animals is NOT in the group?",
            "answer": "Pig"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the intro to Cao Cao’s RoK story, he tells the governor they can call him by another name. What is this name?",
            "answer": "Mengde"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Lohar’s Trial event, how can players obtain Bone Necklaces?",
            "answer": "Defeating ordinary Barbarians"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Peerless Scholar event, how many answers do you need to get correct in the Preliminary to quality for the Midterm?",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the simplified Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, which need is at the top of the pyramid?",
            "answer": "Self-actualization"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the State Forum dispatch “The Duskwoods”, the titular woods are in what direction from the city?",
            "answer": "West"
        },
        {
            "question": "In total, how many goals were scored at the 2018 World Cup?",
            "answer": "169"
        },
        {
            "question": "In total, how many matches were played at the 2018 World Cup?",
            "answer": "64"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what century was a settlement established near the mouth of the Amstel, which would eventually become the city of Amsterdam?",
            "answer": "12th century"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what city did Henri I de Bourbon, Prince of Condé, pass away?",
            "answer": "Saint-Jean-d’Angély"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what climate does basil, known in Europe as the “King of Herbs”, largely grow?",
            "answer": "Tropical areas"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what country did the “Battle of Marengo” take place?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what era of Chinese history did the “Battle of Fei River” take place where a small number of soldiers conquered a vastly superior force?",
            "answer": "The Eastern Jin Dynasty"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did Einstein publish his four Annus Mirabilis (“Miracle Papers”)?",
            "answer": "1905"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did Maradona score his “Hand of God” goal?",
            "answer": "1986"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did Mark Zuckerberg create Facebook?",
            "answer": "2004"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did Qatar host the World Cup?",
            "answer": "2022"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did the current World Cup trophy come into use?",
            "answer": "1974"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did the Late Show with David Letterman first premiere?",
            "answer": "1993"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year was FIFA founded?",
            "answer": "1904"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year was the first Women’s World Cup held?",
            "answer": "1991"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year was the first World Cup held?",
            "answer": "1930"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which century did the classic English dessert sticky toffee pudding originate?",
            "answer": "The mid-20th century"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which city in the United States has McDonald’s established a Hamburger University?",
            "answer": "Chicago"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which city is Denmark’s statue of The Little Mermaid located?",
            "answer": "Copenhagen"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which city is FIFA headquartered?",
            "answer": "Zurich"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which city is the Obelisk of Thutmose III currently held?",
            "answer": "Istanbul"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which city was the world’s first international soccer match held?",
            "answer": "Glasgow"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which commander’s background picture can you see a chicken?",
            "answer": "Queen Tamar of Georgia"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which commander’s background picture can you see a sakura tree?",
            "answer": "Minamoto no Yoshitsune"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country did assam tea, known for its rich aromas, originate?",
            "answer": "India"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country did the “Olé, Olé, Olé” chant originate?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country did the Carlist Wars take place during the 19th century?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country is the Lighthouse of Alexandria, one of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World, located?",
            "answer": "Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country is the mysterious Stonehenge located?",
            "answer": "United Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was air conditioning invented?",
            "answer": "USA"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was Botticelli, painter of The Birth of Venus, born?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was Carlsberg Group, a leading brewer, founded in 1847?",
            "answer": "Denmark"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was mozzarella cheese first produced, broadly associated with Italian cooking and pizzas?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was the 20th World Cup held?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was the electric rice cooker invented?",
            "answer": "Japan"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was the famed revolutionary and military strategist Simón Bolívar born?",
            "answer": "Venezuela"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was the microscope invented?",
            "answer": "The Netherlands"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was the Somme, the most infamous battlefield in World War I, located?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country were the Wars of the Roses fought?",
            "answer": "England"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country were instant noodles first invented?",
            "answer": "Japan"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which English palace did the “Star Chamber” sit?",
            "answer": "Palace of Westminster"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which English stadium was the 1966 World Cup Final held?",
            "answer": "Wembley Stadium"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which era of French history was the Arc de Triomphe built?",
            "answer": "Napoleonic era"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which era was the very first pyramid of ancient Egypt constructed?",
            "answer": "The Third Dynasty of Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which gallery is the Mona Lisa currently held?",
            "answer": "The Louvre"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which lake is Olkhon Island located?",
            "answer": "Lake Baikal"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which language was the Nibelungenlied written?",
            "answer": "Middle High German"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which museum is the painting “The Coronation of Napoleon” currently housed?",
            "answer": "The Louvre"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which of these campaigns did Thutmose III take part?",
            "answer": "The Battle of Megiddo"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which of these works does Sherlock Holmes make his first appearance?",
            "answer": "A Study in Scarlet"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which region did the popular health food hummus originate?",
            "answer": "Middle East"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which region in Italy is the Cathedrawl of Santa Maria del Fiore located?",
            "answer": "Tuscany"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which region was the empire of Srivijaya located?",
            "answer": "Southeast Asia"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which theater was Beethoven’s Symphony No. 5 in C Minor debuted in 1808?",
            "answer": "The Theater an der Wien"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which two years was the World Cup suspended due to World War II?",
            "answer": "1942 & 1946"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which UK city were The Beatles founded in 1960?",
            "answer": "Liverpool"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which World Cup did England captain Harry Kane score 6 goals, earning him the Golden Boot award?",
            "answer": "2018 Russia World Cup"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which World Cup did Spain win its first World Cup?",
            "answer": "2010 South Africa World Cup"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year did Alexander Fleming discover penicillin?",
            "answer": "1928"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year did every World Cup start having a mascot?",
            "answer": "1966"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year did Richard the Lionheart and Saladin sign a truce?",
            "answer": "1192"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the Battle of Guandu?",
            "answer": "200"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the first edition of “The Diary of Anne Frank” published?",
            "answer": "1947"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the first Wimbledon Tennis Championship held?",
            "answer": "1877"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the Napoleonic Code established?",
            "answer": "1804"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the Soviet Union formally established?",
            "answer": "1922"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the Tianwen-1 Mars probe launched?",
            "answer": "2020"
        },
        {
            "question": "In whose court was the “Huainanzi” compiled into a book?",
            "answer": "Liu An"
        },
        {
            "question": "In whose workshop did Leonardo da Vinci apprentice?",
            "answer": "Andrea del Verrocchio"
        },
        {
            "question": "Insufficient intake of which element may cause the thyromegaly?",
            "answer": "Iodine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Into what kind of deity was Imhotep deified following his death?",
            "answer": "A god of medicine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Into what shape does commander Yi Seong-Gye’s fan-shaped active skill transform after gaining Expertise?",
            "answer": "A circle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Japanese ivy grows upward on walls and trees in order to capture energy from which source?",
            "answer": "Sunlight"
        },
        {
            "question": "Johannes Vermeer, the painter of Girl with a Pearl Earring, was from which country?",
            "answer": "The Netherlands"
        },
        {
            "question": "Keira once defied the world’s expectations about her in a glorious battle. Where did this battle take place?",
            "answer": "Sunset Canyon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Lactose intolerance is caused by a shortage of what?",
            "answer": "Lactase"
        },
        {
            "question": "Legendary commander of the Joseon Dynasty, Yi Sun-sin, sacrificed his life in which famous battle?",
            "answer": "Legendary commander of the Joseon Dynasty, Yi Sun-sin, sacrificed his life in which famous battle?"
        },
        {
            "question": "Li Xin, the ancestor of the “Flying General” Li Guang, was a general of which state during the Warring States period of Chinese history?",
            "answer": "Qin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Llamas are native to which Earth continent?",
            "answer": "South America"
        },
        {
            "question": "Messi has used 6 different jersey numbers in his career. What are those 6 numbers?",
            "answer": "10, 14, 15, 18, 19, 30"
        },
        {
            "question": "Methods of mitigating desertification do NOT include:",
            "answer": "Overexploitation of groundwater"
        },
        {
            "question": "Military strategist Belisarius served as a personal bodyguard to which emperor in his youth?",
            "answer": "Justinianus I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Miroslav Klose holds the record for most goals scored in the World Cup. How many goals has he scored?",
            "answer": "16"
        },
        {
            "question": "Murasaki is a character in which of the following works?",
            "answer": "Tale of Genji"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mutations are important because they bring about what?",
            "answer": "Genetic variation needed for a population to evolve"
        },
        {
            "question": "Northern Humanists like Erasmus were most commonly known for what?",
            "answer": "Interest in religious and social reform"
        },
        {
            "question": "Noted Danish archaeologist Christian Jürgensen Thomsen proposed the “three ages” system for categorizing ancient history. Which is the first stage?",
            "answer": "Stone Age"
        },
        {
            "question": "Of the 12 Chinese Zodiac animals, which comes first?",
            "answer": "Rat"
        },
        {
            "question": "Of the below commanders, which is best suited to lead troops AGAINST archer enemies?",
            "answer": "Cao Cao"
        },
        {
            "question": "Of the below commanders, which is best suited to lead troops AGAINST cavalry enemies?",
            "answer": "Sun Tzu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Of the below commanders, which is best suited to lead troops AGAINST infantry enemies?",
            "answer": "Hermann"
        },
        {
            "question": "Of the below commanders, which is best suited to lead troops when gathering resources?",
            "answer": "Seondeok"
        },
        {
            "question": "Of the following, which is most likely to have directly led to the Bronze Age?",
            "answer": "Bronze is harder and more durable than other metals available at the time"
        },
        {
            "question": "On average, which of the following animals is the largest?",
            "answer": "Blue whale"
        },
        {
            "question": "On average, which of the following animals is the smallest?",
            "answer": "Ant"
        },
        {
            "question": "On its tragic maiden voyage, what was the Titanic’s intended destination?",
            "answer": "New York"
        },
        {
            "question": "On which animal was the 2018 Russia World Cup’s mascot based on?",
            "answer": "Wolf"
        },
        {
            "question": "On which continent did the serval first live?",
            "answer": "Africa"
        },
        {
            "question": "On which continent is Benin located?",
            "answer": "Africa"
        },
        {
            "question": "On which continent is the human race generally thought to have originated?",
            "answer": "Africa"
        },
        {
            "question": "On which ingredient was the 1986 Mexico World Cup’s mascot based on?",
            "answer": "Pepper"
        },
        {
            "question": "One “day” on the planet Venus is approximately equal to how many earth days?",
            "answer": "243 days"
        },
        {
            "question": "One of the benefits of canned food is its long shelf life. Where were the first canned herrings made?",
            "answer": "Northern Europe"
        },
        {
            "question": "Pandas have 5 clawed toes on as well as a sixth digit. What do pandas use their sixth digit for?",
            "answer": "To hold bamboo while eating"
        },
        {
            "question": "Passport Pages are used when immigrating to other Kingdoms. What does the number of Passport Pages used depend on?",
            "answer": "Governor’s Individual Power"
        },
        {
            "question": "Peppers have been farmed for millennia. Which continent can we trace their origins back to?",
            "answer": "The Americas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Qatar follows Arabia Standard Time. How would that be notated using UTC?",
            "answer": "UTC+3:00"
        },
        {
            "question": "Queen Guinevere fell in love with which Knight of the Round Table according to Arthurian legend?",
            "answer": "Lancelot"
        },
        {
            "question": "Queen Victoria of England was part of which royal house?",
            "answer": "The House of Hanover"
        },
        {
            "question": "Raphael is best known for his creation of which of the following?",
            "answer": "School of Athens"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sandro Botticelli’s painting “Venus and Mars” is famed for its vivid colors and beautiful figures. In which gallery is this painting now housed?",
            "answer": "The National Gallery in London"
        },
        {
            "question": "Santa Claus travels on a sleigh pulled by what animal?",
            "answer": "Reindeer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Screenwriter Marguerite Duras is known for writing the film “Hiroshima mon amour”. Where was she born?",
            "answer": "Vietnam"
        },
        {
            "question": "Seondeok was Queen of Silla (part of modern-day Korea). What was her birth name?",
            "answer": "Kim Deokman"
        },
        {
            "question": "Shanghai’s Jin Mao Tower has how many floors?",
            "answer": "88"
        },
        {
            "question": "Since its founding in 1863, how many times has the International Committee of the Red Cross won the Nobel Peace Prize?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "Some toothpastes contain powdered calcium carbonate. What is its function?",
            "answer": "Acts as an abrasive"
        },
        {
            "question": "Thanks to large deposits of borax and pigment from local algae, the Laguna Colorada is a fantastical landscape of red and white. What country is it located in?",
            "answer": "Bolivia"
        },
        {
            "question": "The “Battle of Las Navas de Tolosa” was a major turning point in which conflict?",
            "answer": "The Reconquista"
        },
        {
            "question": "The “Beef Wellington” involves cooking filet mignon wrapped inside which other ingredient?",
            "answer": "Puff pastry"
        },
        {
            "question": "The “Day of the Tiles” is regarded by some historians to mark the beginning of the French Revolution. In what city did it take place?",
            "answer": "Grenoble"
        },
        {
            "question": "The “Dragonfly Cutter” was the weapon of choice of which legendary warrior?",
            "answer": "Honda Tadakatsu"
        },
        {
            "question": "The “eight queens puzzle” is a classic use-case for which category of algorithms?",
            "answer": "Backtracking algorithms"
        },
        {
            "question": "The “El Nino” phenomenon is named after which of these festivals?",
            "answer": "Christmas"
        },
        {
            "question": "The “Independence March” is the national anthem of which country?",
            "answer": "Turkey"
        },
        {
            "question": "The “Three Great Philosophers” of Ancient Greece were Plato, Aristotle, and who?",
            "answer": "Socrates"
        },
        {
            "question": "The “Windsor knot” was made popular by which king of England?",
            "answer": "Edward VIII"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 1,000 point achievement chest includes:",
            "answer": "Epic Commander Sculpture"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 2022 World Cup will be the first men’s world cup with female referees. How many will there by?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 24 “solar terms” are a traditional Chinese calendar system used for what purpose?",
            "answer": "Agriculture"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Academy Awards occasionally presents the Jean Hersholt Humanitarian Award. Which of these films was Jean Hersholt in?",
            "answer": "Greed (1924)"
        },
        {
            "question": "The air often feels fresher after a thunderstorm because it has been enriched with which gas?",
            "answer": "Ozone"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Alliance Technology “Territory Guardian” increases which attribute of troops when battling in Alliance territory?",
            "answer": "Attack"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Ancient Olympic Games were held every 4 years at Olympia, in southwest Greece. In what year are they believed to have begun?",
            "answer": "776 BCE"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Aral Sea was once the world’s fourth largest lake, but since then it has mostly dried up. Where is it located?",
            "answer": "Central Asia"
        },
        {
            "question": "The auction house Sotheby’s was founded in 1744 in which English city?",
            "answer": "London"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Bastille, a prison once located in the center of Paris, France, originally served what purpose?",
            "answer": "Defensive Fortress"
        },
        {
            "question": "The blueprint fragments of which of the following accessories CANNOT be redeemed from the Season of Conquest Shop?",
            "answer": "Pendant of Eternal Night"
        },
        {
            "question": "The borders of which of these countries extend across two continents?",
            "answer": "Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "The cathedral of Notre-Dame de Paris was built in which style?",
            "answer": "Gothic"
        },
        {
            "question": "The character of “Robin Hood” first appeared in the folklore of which country?",
            "answer": "England"
        },
        {
            "question": "The city decoration “Ishtar Gate” is a tribute to which of the following civilizations?",
            "answer": "Babylonia"
        },
        {
            "question": "The coffee bean is in fact a type of…?",
            "answer": "Fruit"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Colossus of Rhodes depicts which god of the sun?",
            "answer": "Helios"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Colossus of Rhodes represents which Greek god?",
            "answer": "Helios"
        },
        {
            "question": "The concept of ‘separation of powers’ comes from which work by Montesquieu?",
            "answer": "The Spirit of Law"
        },
        {
            "question": "The cone-shaped winds of tornadoes are notable for doing what?",
            "answer": "Spinning"
        },
        {
            "question": "The daily physical activities of the Maya people did NOT include:",
            "answer": "Penguin tossing"
        },
        {
            "question": "The depth at the deepest point of the Baltic Sea is:",
            "answer": "459m"
        },
        {
            "question": "The epic “Poem of El Cid” originated from which country?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "The famous Renaissance sculpture Pietà was the work of which artist?",
            "answer": "Michelangelo"
        },
        {
            "question": "The flag of which country holds the world record of being the oldest continuously used national flag?",
            "answer": "Denmark"
        },
        {
            "question": "The four biggest musicals in the world are Cats, Les Miserables, Miss Saigon, and…?",
            "answer": "The Phantom of the Opera"
        },
        {
            "question": "The four major varieties of Guzheng in Ancient China were the Haozhong, Luqi, Jiaowei, and the…?",
            "answer": "Raoliang"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Gallic rooster is an official national symbol of which country?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "The General Carrera Lake originates from the Andes glaciers. Which two countries border the lake?",
            "answer": "Argentina and Chile"
        },
        {
            "question": "The general theory of relativity was published by which physicist?",
            "answer": "Einstein"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Golden Bear Award is given out at which film festival?",
            "answer": "Berlin Film Festival"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Golden Glove/Lev Yashin award is given to the best goalkeeper in the World Cup. In which World Cup was it first awarded?",
            "answer": "15th"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Gothic alphabet was developed by which bishop?",
            "answer": "Ulfilas"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Greek alphabet originated from which other writing system?",
            "answer": "Phoenician"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Greek epic The Odyssey records the return of the hero Odysseus from war. Where was his homeland?",
            "answer": "Ithaca"
        },
        {
            "question": "The kingdom title ‘Queen’ increases which of the following?",
            "answer": "Gathering Speed"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Leaning Tower of Pisa is located in which of these countries?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Lion Gate is the largest surviving prehistoric sculpture in the Aegean. Where is it located?",
            "answer": "Mycenae"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Luger pistol, manufactured for the German army during WW2, uses which type of ammo?",
            "answer": "9mm Parabellum"
        },
        {
            "question": "The mascot of the 2010 South Africa World Cup was an anthropomorphic leopard with green hair. What was his name?",
            "answer": "Zakumi"
        },
        {
            "question": "The military leader Charles Martel was NOT known for which of the following?",
            "answer": "Leading cavalry units"
        },
        {
            "question": "The more genetic variation a population has, the more likely it is that some individual will what?",
            "answer": "Survive"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Mughal Empire carried Islam to where?",
            "answer": "Most of India"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Museum of Modern Art is located in which American city?",
            "answer": "New York"
        },
        {
            "question": "The novel Romance of the Three Kingdoms begins near the end of which Chinese dynasty?",
            "answer": "Han"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Pantheon has been the burial site of many important artists since the Renaissance. Which of the following artists were buried there?",
            "answer": "Raphael"
        },
        {
            "question": "The period after the fall of the Mycenaean civilization and before the birth of the Greek city-states is known as the Greek Dark Ages. Which of these works was written during that time?",
            "answer": "The Odyssey"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Phoenician civilization originated in which part of the world?",
            "answer": "The Eastern Mediterranean"
        },
        {
            "question": "The poet Fernando Pessoa was known for writing his poems as different “characters”, which he called “heteronyms”. Which of these is NOT one of the heteronyms that Pessoa used?",
            "answer": "Francisco Norman"
        },
        {
            "question": "The prehistoric humans known as “homo floresiensis” are also commonly referred to as?",
            "answer": "Hobbits"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process of combining atoms is known as what?",
            "answer": "Fusion"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process of splitting atoms is known as?",
            "answer": "Fission"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Punic Wars were fought by Ancient Rome and what other ancient empire?",
            "answer": "Ancient Carthage"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Qingming Riverside Map captures the daily life and landscape of which ancient Chinese dynasty?",
            "answer": "The Song"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Renaissance was a “rebirth” of what?",
            "answer": "Classical culture"
        },
        {
            "question": "The saying “The Empire on which the sun never sets” was originally used in reference to which country’s empire?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Scoville scale is often used to rate the spiciness of peppers, a higher value denoting greater spiciness. Which of these peppers is rated at over 1 million on the Scoville scale?",
            "answer": "Soul pepper"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Singing Sand Dunes in Dunhuang, China are known for making a loud drumming sound whenever the wind blows. What desert are they a part of?",
            "answer": "Kumtag Desert"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Taj Mahal was built during which Indian Dynasty?",
            "answer": "The Mughal Dynasty"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Tang dynasty style of pottery decoration known as “sancai” primarily uses which three colors?",
            "answer": "Yellow, green, white"
        },
        {
            "question": "The theory of general relativity encounters difficulties when applied to:",
            "answer": "Subatomic particles"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Third Punic War led to the downfall of which state?",
            "answer": "Carthage"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Three Kingdoms of Korea were Baekje, Silla, and …?",
            "answer": "Goguryeo"
        },
        {
            "question": "The two capitals of Austria-Hungary were Budapest and which other city?",
            "answer": "Vienna"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Uruguay national team displays four stars on its emblems. How many World Cups has it won?",
            "answer": "Two"
        },
        {
            "question": "The writer of ‘A Song of Ice and Fire’ recently contributed to the script of which video game?",
            "answer": "Elden Ring"
        },
        {
            "question": "The zeppelin was invented by engineers from which country?",
            "answer": "Germany"
        },
        {
            "question": "To unlock the achievement “Huarong Trail”, you must use Guan Yu to defeat a troop led by which of the following commanders?",
            "answer": "Cao Cao"
        },
        {
            "question": "To whom did India give the title “Mahatma”?",
            "answer": "Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Tokugawa Ieyasu and who else became the three “Great Unifiers” of Japan?",
            "answer": "Oda Nobunaga and Toyotomi Hideyoshi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Under normal circumstances, which layer of the Sun can we see with the naked eye?",
            "answer": "Photosphere"
        },
        {
            "question": "Under which category does the formal writing system of ancient Egypt fall?",
            "answer": "Hieroglyphic"
        },
        {
            "question": "Under which Pharaoh did ancient Egyptian minister Imhotep serve?",
            "answer": "Zoser"
        },
        {
            "question": "Using a troop led by Julius Caesar and Cleopatra VII, which of the f ollowing actions will unlock the achievement “Immortal Longings”?",
            "answer": "Attack a city"
        },
        {
            "question": "Wales officially became part of the Kingdom of Great Britain during the reign of which King?",
            "answer": "Henry VIII"
        },
        {
            "question": "What achievement would spending over 200 Golden Keys in the Tavern in a single transaction unlock?",
            "answer": "All In"
        },
        {
            "question": "What age did ancient Greece enter after the Mycenaean civilization was destroyed?",
            "answer": "Dark Age"
        },
        {
            "question": "What ancient Roman ruin located in Algeria was formally assigned World Heritage status in 1982?",
            "answer": "The ruins of Djemila"
        },
        {
            "question": "What animal is the mascot of the 2022 Winter Olympics based on?",
            "answer": "Panda"
        },
        {
            "question": "What animal is the “Tigris” named after in ancient Greek?",
            "answer": "Tiger"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are Arrows of Resistance used for?",
            "answer": "To upgrade the Watchtower"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are Books of Covenant used for?",
            "answer": "To upgrade the Castle"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the dimensions of the fog cleared by a Kingdom Map item?",
            "answer": "10×10"
        },
        {
            "question": "What benefit does researching “Mathematics” in the Academy provide?",
            "answer": "Increased research speed"
        },
        {
            "question": "What can “Masonry” technology help you to improve?",
            "answer": "The building speed of buildings in your city"
        },
        {
            "question": "What caused the death of the outstanding statemen and military strategist, Pericles?",
            "answer": "A plague"
        },
        {
            "question": "What caused the deaths of Ceroli Chieftain Dekar’s parents?",
            "answer": "The discovery of their witchcraft studies"
        },
        {
            "question": "What causes lunar eclipses?",
            "answer": "The earth moves directly between the sun and the moon"
        },
        {
            "question": "What civilization developed between the Tigris and Euphrates rivers?",
            "answer": "The Mesopotamians"
        },
        {
            "question": "What color are the fresh flowers in the Lyceum of Wisdom for the French civilization?",
            "answer": "Red"
        },
        {
            "question": "What color are the wings on the Pegasus decoration?",
            "answer": "Gold"
        },
        {
            "question": "What color gemstones are engraved upon the crown of the commander El Cid?",
            "answer": "Red"
        },
        {
            "question": "What color is a polar bear’s skin?",
            "answer": "Black"
        },
        {
            "question": "What color is used on the roofs of buildings in the Japanese civilization?",
            "answer": "Black"
        },
        {
            "question": "What color paint was favored by ancient Egyptian families for the walls of their homes?",
            "answer": "White"
        },
        {
            "question": "What color sail did Theseus fly on his ship to signify to his father Aegeus that he had successfully slain the Minotaur?",
            "answer": "White"
        },
        {
            "question": "What color was the match ball used in the 1966 World Cup Final?",
            "answer": "Orange"
        },
        {
            "question": "What country did the infamous pirate Blackbeard come from?",
            "answer": "England"
        },
        {
            "question": "What country is not in Europe?",
            "answer": "Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "What country was Sigmund Freud, the father of psychoanalysis, from?",
            "answer": "Austria"
        },
        {
            "question": "What date is World Environment Day held each year?",
            "answer": "June 5th"
        },
        {
            "question": "What did Che Guevara study in college?",
            "answer": "Medicine"
        },
        {
            "question": "What did Spartacus do as a slave before leading the biggest slave rebellion of Ancient Rome?",
            "answer": "A gladiator"
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the name for ancient Egypt’s Luxor Temple also mean?",
            "answer": "The southern sanctuary"
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the word “marathon” originally refer to?",
            "answer": "A place name"
        },
        {
            "question": "What did Theodorus van Gogh, the younger brother of famed Dutch painter Vincent Van Gogh, do for a living?",
            "answer": "Art Dealer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What discovery made the deciphering of hieroglyphics possible?",
            "answer": "The Rosetta Stone"
        },
        {
            "question": "What do Dragon Lancers carry in their left hand?",
            "answer": "A tobacco pipe"
        },
        {
            "question": "What do you have to do to earn the Witness Protection achievement?",
            "answer": "Change your nickname 10 times"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does a “hat-trick” mean in soccer?",
            "answer": "One player scoring 3 goals for their team"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the ankh character represent in ancient Egyptian hieroglyphics?",
            "answer": "Life"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the word “Formula” in “Formula 1 Racing” refer to?",
            "answer": "The rules which participating cars must follow"
        },
        {
            "question": "What event marked the beginning of the Hellenistic period?",
            "answer": "The death of Alexander the Great"
        },
        {
            "question": "What four-word saying did Oda Nobunaga live by?",
            "answer": "Rule With absolute force"
        },
        {
            "question": "What honorary rank was the founder of Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC) given?",
            "answer": "Colonel"
        },
        {
            "question": "What image is engraved on the Hammer of the Sun and Moon weapon?",
            "answer": "The sun"
        },
        {
            "question": "What information does the item Deceptive Troops falsify for enemy Scouts?",
            "answer": "Your City’s unit count"
        },
        {
            "question": "What ingredients are used to make “zongzi”, a traditional food eaten in China during the Dragon Boat Festival?",
            "answer": "Glutinous rice"
        },
        {
            "question": "What instrument was officially banned by FIFA after the 2010 South Africa World Cup?",
            "answer": "Vuvuzela"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a “light-year” a measure of?",
            "answer": "Distance"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is an alternate name for the novel “Dream of the Red Chamber”?",
            "answer": "The Story of the Stone"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Belisarius’ nickname?",
            "answer": "Last of the Romans"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is China’s earliest known book of military strategy?",
            "answer": "Sun Tzu’s “The Art of War”"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Commander Baibars good at?",
            "answer": "Leading cavalry units"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Commander Cao Cao’s expertise skill called?",
            "answer": "Emperor Wu of Wei"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Commander Eulji Mundeok good at?",
            "answer": "Leading infantry units"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Commander Hermann good at?",
            "answer": "Leading archer units"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Commander Keira good at?",
            "answer": "Leading archer units"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Commander Lancelot good at?",
            "answer": "Leading cavalry units"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Commander Osman I good at?",
            "answer": "Attacking cities"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Commander Sun Tzu good at?",
            "answer": "Leading city garrisons"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Julius Caesar’s nickname?",
            "answer": "The Uncrowned King"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Julius Caesar’s nickname in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "The Uncrowned Emperor"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Karaku’s Fire Shaman called?",
            "answer": "Denko"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the 2nd-largest constituent nation of the United Kingdom?",
            "answer": "Scotland"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the actual name of Dmitri Shostakovich’s symphony “Leningrad”?",
            "answer": "Symphony No. 7 in C major"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the alliance rally capacity provided by a Lvl 15 Fort?",
            "answer": "775,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the alternative name of Shakespeare’s play Twelfth Night?",
            "answer": "What You Will"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the bonus provided by the Frozen Fortress legendary city theme?",
            "answer": "Infantry Defense +10%"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the capital of the Republic of Chile?",
            "answer": "Santiago"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the center of a hurricane called?",
            "answer": "Eye"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the champion Keira’s nickname?",
            "answer": "The Red Chameleon"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the chemical symbol of antimony?",
            "answer": "Sb"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Chinese zodiac sign for the lunar year starting on February 10, 2024?",
            "answer": "Dragon"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the closest star system to the solar system?",
            "answer": "Alpha Centauri"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the color of the floral headdress worn by commander Šárka in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "Red"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the color of the jade pendant around the commander Cao Cao’s waist?",
            "answer": "Green"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Commander Hannibal Barca good at?",
            "answer": "Attacking cities"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the conversion ratio of amperes (A) to milliamperes (mA)?",
            "answer": "0.736111111"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the default rallied troop capacity when your castle is level 25?",
            "answer": "2 million"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the default transportation capacity if your trading post is level 25?",
            "answer": "5 million"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the duration of the Builder Recruitment item?",
            "answer": "2 days"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the effect of the accessory “Vengeance”?",
            "answer": "Counterattack Damage +8%"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Expertise Skill of the commander Alexander the Great called?",
            "answer": "Son of Amun"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Gem cost of the Human Sculpture decoration?",
            "answer": "2,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the half-life of Iodine-129, a radioactive isotope produced by nuclear reactors?",
            "answer": "15.7 million years"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the hardest part of the human body?",
            "answer": "Tooth Enamel"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the heaviest alkaline earth metal?",
            "answer": "Radium"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the highest island peak in the world?",
            "answer": "Puncak Jaya"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the highest level a City Hall can reach in RoK?",
            "answer": "25"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the highest mountain in Africa?",
            "answer": "Mount Kilimanjaro"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the in-game nickname of Cleopatra VII?",
            "answer": "Queen of Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest airport in the world by area?",
            "answer": "King Fahd International Airport"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest animal on the planet?",
            "answer": "Blue whale"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest city in the UK by area?",
            "answer": "London"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest country in South America?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest freshwater lake in the world by area?",
            "answer": "Lake Superior"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest known planet in our solar system?",
            "answer": "Jupiter"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest lake in Europe?",
            "answer": "Lake Ladoga"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest lake on the South American continent?",
            "answer": "Lake Maracaibo"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest living species of bird in the world?",
            "answer": "Ostrich"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest planet in our solar system?",
            "answer": "Jupiter"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the length of a marathon in kilometers?",
            "answer": "42.2 Km"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the main ingredient in salt?",
            "answer": "Sodium chloride"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the main ingredient of popcorn?",
            "answer": "Corn"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the main purpose of white blood cells in the human body?",
            "answer": "Fighting infection and disease"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the maximum number of King’s Road decorative buildings a governor can construct?",
            "answer": "400"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the maximum number of troops you can form in the Champions of Olympia event?",
            "answer": "9"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the maximum period of time that alliance resources can accumulate for in the Alliance Territory screen?",
            "answer": "24h"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the minimum number of Silver Keys that can be obtained from the “Treasure of Wisdom” bundle?",
            "answer": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the most abundant element in earth’s crust?",
            "answer": "Oxygen"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the most abundant substance in the body of a healthy adult?",
            "answer": "Water"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name for electricity produced by water power using large dams in a river?",
            "answer": "Hydroelectric energy"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name for renewable energy derived from burning organic materials such as wood and alcohol?",
            "answer": "Biomass"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name for the innermost sanctum of an ancient Greek temple, accessible only to members of the priesthood?",
            "answer": "Adyton"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name for the phenomenon by which organisms that are better adapted to the environment survive to pass traits to their offspring?",
            "answer": "Natural selection"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the 2022 Qatar World Cup mascot?",
            "answer": "La’eeb"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the achievement obtained by acquiring 3 permanent city themes?",
            "answer": "Technicolor Themes"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the fourth bracket in the “Champions of Olympia” event?",
            "answer": "Brilliant Silver"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the revolution in 1688 which established the British constitutional monarchy?",
            "answer": "The Glorious Revolution"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the swindler who can also appear at the same time as the Ceroli Chieftain Bloodfist Bargha?",
            "answer": "Dhalruk"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the Turkish straits that divide Europe from Asia?",
            "answer": "The Bosphorus"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the nationality of Pierre de Fermat, who proposed Fermat’s Last Theorem?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the only country to have won both the Men’s and Women’s World Cup?",
            "answer": "Germany"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the only known short-period comet that is regularly visible to the naked eye from Earth?",
            "answer": "Halley’s Comet"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the optimal temperature for roasting a chicken on the sizzling barrel of an Ottoman cannon?",
            "answer": "200°C"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the primary cause of karst landforms?",
            "answer": "The dissolution of soluble rocks"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the relationship between diamonds and graphite?",
            "answer": "They are both allotropes of carbon"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the root cause of altitude sickness?",
            "answer": "Rapid exposure to low amounts of oxygen at high elevation"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the shape of a soccer goal when viewed from the front?",
            "answer": "A rectangle"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the slogan of the weapons manufacturer Heckler & Koch?",
            "answer": "“No Compromises!”"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the softest mineral currently known to mankind?",
            "answer": "Talc"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the southernmost point of Africa?",
            "answer": "Cape Agulhas"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the tallest and heaviest living penguin species?",
            "answer": "Emperor penguin"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the tallest peak in the world?",
            "answer": "Mount Everest"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the total Lvl 25 Hospital Capacity for severely wounded troops (excluding boosts)?",
            "answer": "300,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the unlock condition for Nightmare difficulty in the “Ian’s Ballads” event?",
            "answer": "Reach City Hall Lvl 23 and 20 million Power"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the VIP Level required to purchase a Legendary Commander Sculpture on a weekly discount from the VIP Shop?",
            "answer": "Lvl 13"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the world’s oldest film festival?",
            "answer": "Venice Film Festival"
        },
        {
            "question": "What item summons Dauntless Lohar?",
            "answer": "Lohar’s Buckler"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of animal was the mascot of the 1998 World Cup in France?",
            "answer": "Cockerel"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of boost to allied forces does commander Joan of Arc’s active skill provide?",
            "answer": "Rage"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of combat blessing do Archers receive in Champions of Olympia?",
            "answer": "The Blessing of Ares"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of combat blessing do Cavalry receive in Champions of Olympia?",
            "answer": "The Blessing of Hades"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of combat blessing do Infantry receive in Champions of Olympia?",
            "answer": "The Blessing of Athena"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of combat blessing do mixed units receive in Champions of Olympia?",
            "answer": "The Blessing of Apollo"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of commander becomes the temporary Garrison Commander in the event a Governor has not nominated a commander or the nominated commander is not present?",
            "answer": "The highest level commander currently present"
        },
        {
            "question": "What letter is shown on the Scolas’ Lucky Coin decoration?",
            "answer": "L"
        },
        {
            "question": "What level do you need to upgrade the State Forum to in order to unlock the Dispatch feature?",
            "answer": "10"
        },
        {
            "question": "What level does your City Hall have to be to enter the Iron Age?",
            "answer": "Lvl 10"
        },
        {
            "question": "What level does your City Hall have to be to use War Frenzy?",
            "answer": "10"
        },
        {
            "question": "What material did the craftsmen of ancient Egypt favor for sculpting statues and murals?",
            "answer": "Stone"
        },
        {
            "question": "What nationality was Miguel de Cervantes, author of “Don Quixote”?",
            "answer": "Spanish"
        },
        {
            "question": "What number World Cup will the 2022 World Cup be?",
            "answer": "22nd"
        },
        {
            "question": "What occupation buff is provided by the Flame Altar?",
            "answer": "Troop Attack +3%"
        },
        {
            "question": "What outstanding contribution to science won biologist Karl Landsteiner the Nobel Prize?",
            "answer": "Discovering the human blood groups"
        },
        {
            "question": "What process is responsible for the red hues of the eponymous Red Sea?",
            "answer": "Unusual algae"
        },
        {
            "question": "What provided the major economic support for the Renaissance?",
            "answer": "Wealthy patrons"
        },
        {
            "question": "What race of creatures, mythical or otherwise, lived on Asgard according to Norse myth?",
            "answer": "Aesir"
        },
        {
            "question": "What resource is required to travel in the State Forum?",
            "answer": "Action Points"
        },
        {
            "question": "What reward may be given to governors who do NOT qualify for the Ark of Osiris but whose fellow alliance members do qualify and are defeated?",
            "answer": "Gems"
        },
        {
            "question": "What taxonomic order do Eurasian tree sparrows belong to?",
            "answer": "Passeriformes"
        },
        {
            "question": "What tier of crystal treasure is found in the Lvl 26 Alliance Gift?",
            "answer": "Treasure of Blue Crystal"
        },
        {
            "question": "What two countries together made up the “Iberian Union”?",
            "answer": "Portugal and Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "What two major works are attributed to Homer?",
            "answer": "The Odyssey and The Iliad"
        },
        {
            "question": "What useful tool did famed carpenter Lu Ban invent?",
            "answer": "The saw"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was another usage of gin, aside from being a popular drink, in the 18th century?",
            "answer": "Medicine"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the country of origin of the architect who designed the Museum of Egyptian Antiquities located in Cairo?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the first animated film Satoshi Kon directed?",
            "answer": "Perfect Blue"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the final score of the 2014 World Cup final between Germany and Argentina?",
            "answer": "1 – 0"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the first men’s World Cup to have a female referee?",
            "answer": "2022 Qatar World Cup"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the first of the three major battles fought between Alexander the Great and the Achaemenid Empire?",
            "answer": "Battle of the Granicus"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the first war to be called “The war to end all wars”?",
            "answer": "World War I"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the first World Cup trophy called?",
            "answer": "Jules Rimet Trophy"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the homeland of Odysseus, the subject of Homer’s Odyssey?",
            "answer": "Ithaca"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the alliance led by Athens in the Peloponnesian War?",
            "answer": "Delian League"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the ancient Greek god of wine?",
            "answer": "Dionysus"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the creature in Greek mythology that lured sailors with its heavenly singing voice?",
            "answer": "Siren"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the first chimpanzee to go to space?",
            "answer": "Ham"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the official match ball of the 2018 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Telstar"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the native language of Cleopatra VII, otherwise known as Cleopatra the Queen of Egypt?",
            "answer": "Greek"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the original purpose of the Great Pyramid of Giza?",
            "answer": "Pharaoh Khufu’s tomb"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the regnal name of the last emperor of China’s Qing Dynasty?",
            "answer": "Xuantong"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the relationship between the famed generals Tolui and Genghis Khan?",
            "answer": "Father and son"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the venue for the final match of the 2018 World Cup held in Russia?",
            "answer": "Luzhniki Stadium, Moscow"
        },
        {
            "question": "What weapon does the commander Richard I wield?",
            "answer": "An axe and shield"
        },
        {
            "question": "What weapons do City Keepers wield?",
            "answer": "An axe and shield"
        },
        {
            "question": "What weapons does the commander City Keeper wield?",
            "answer": "An axe and shield"
        },
        {
            "question": "What were Maya pyramids made of?",
            "answer": "Stone"
        },
        {
            "question": "What were the men and women hiding from on the outskirts of Florence in the novella collection “The Decameron”?",
            "answer": "The Black Plague"
        },
        {
            "question": "What’s does the “Fully Loaded” alliance skill do when used?",
            "answer": "Increases alliance members’ gathering speed for one type of resource"
        },
        {
            "question": "What’s does the “Nature’s Gift” alliance skill do when used?",
            "answer": "Summon resource points in a selected area"
        },
        {
            "question": "What’s does the “Skillful Craftsman” alliance skill do when used?",
            "answer": "Greatly increases alliance flag construction speed"
        },
        {
            "question": "What’s the primary cause of the formation of the Himalayas?",
            "answer": "Collision between plates"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a governor’s city hall reaches level 25, how many farms can they build?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "When Achilles refuses to fight, Patroclus puts on Achilles armor, fights the Trojans, and dies. Who is Patroclus killed by?",
            "answer": "Hector"
        },
        {
            "question": "When alliance members gather resources in alliance territory, how much is their Gathering Speed increased by?",
            "answer": "25%"
        },
        {
            "question": "When did the “hard-boiled” or “noir” literary genre of fiction first fluorish?",
            "answer": "1920s"
        },
        {
            "question": "When did the War of the Austrian Succession take place?",
            "answer": "1740-1748"
        },
        {
            "question": "When moist air encounters an obstacle such as a mountain range and is forced upward while air temperature drops, resulting in rain, this is known as:",
            "answer": "Orographic precipitation"
        },
        {
            "question": "When not affected by buffs, how much resource capacity does a Level 25 Storehouse have for each type of resource?",
            "answer": "2,500,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "When sailing through a thunderstorm, one can occasionally see a “lightning” effect at the tip of the mast. What is this phenomenon called?",
            "answer": "Saint Elmo’s Fire"
        },
        {
            "question": "When someone steps on a banana peel wearing shoes, the frictional coefficient between their shoe and the banana peel is:",
            "answer": "0.07"
        },
        {
            "question": "When upgrading your Storehouse from Lvl 24 to Lvl 25, which resource gains the most resource protection capacity?",
            "answer": "Gold"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was Coca-Cola invented?",
            "answer": "The 19th century"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was Napoleon Bonaparte born?",
            "answer": "1769"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Declaration of Independence written?",
            "answer": "1776"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the first Venice Film Festival held?",
            "answer": "1932"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the last time a human walked on the Moon?",
            "answer": "1972"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the theremin, one of the first electronic musical instruments, invented?",
            "answer": "1919"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the Union of South American Nations (UNASUR) officially established?",
            "answer": "2008"
        },
        {
            "question": "When were bicycles introduced to Europe?",
            "answer": "The 19th century"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where are the world’s largest proven oil reserves located?",
            "answer": "Ghawar Field"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where did Hippocrates, the “Father of Medicine”, come from?",
            "answer": "Ancient Greece"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where did King Louis XIV of France move the royal Court to in 1682?",
            "answer": "The Palace of Versailles"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where did reggae music originate?",
            "answer": "Jamaica"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where did the final battle between King Arthur and Mordred take place according to Arthurian legend?",
            "answer": "Camlann"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where did the Renaissance begin?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where do adaptations come from?",
            "answer": "Both mutations and genetic recombination"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where do most hurricanes start?",
            "answer": "On the open seas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where do most of the Ainu people live?",
            "answer": "Hokkaido"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where in Egypt is the Sphinx located?",
            "answer": "The Giza Plateau"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where in Italy is Vatican City located?",
            "answer": "Rome"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the Capital of Scotland?",
            "answer": "Edinburgh"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the capital of the Germany?",
            "answer": "Berlin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the commander Gaius Marius from?",
            "answer": "Ancient Rome"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the largest pyramid in the world?",
            "answer": "The Great Pyramid of Cholula"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the Mausoleum of the First Qin Emperor located in China?",
            "answer": "Shaanxi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the reported birthplace of the belly dance?",
            "answer": "Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the right hand of the famous sculpture known as “The Thinker” resting?",
            "answer": "Under the chin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was Commander Lohar born?",
            "answer": "In a remote barbarian tribe"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was famed musician Beethoven born?",
            "answer": "Bonn"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was Napoleon Bonaparte exiled after his defeat at Waterloo?",
            "answer": "St. Helena"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was Pablo Picasso born?",
            "answer": "Iberia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was the Ceroli Chieftain Torgny born?",
            "answer": "Citadel of Braves"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was the composer Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart born?",
            "answer": "Salzburg"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was the rallying point for the first Crusade?",
            "answer": "Constantinople"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was the World Heritage Terracotta Army found?",
            "answer": "In a royal mausoleum"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which achievement is unlocked from upgrading 2 hospitals to Lvl 25?",
            "answer": "Hale & Hearty"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Chinese dynasty followed the Shang dynasty?",
            "answer": "The Zhou Dynasty"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient civilization built the “Lost City” of Machu Picchu?",
            "answer": "The Incas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Egyptian deity is represented with the head of a lion?",
            "answer": "Tefnut"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Egyptian pharaoh’s tomb did British archaeologist Howard Carter discover in 1922?",
            "answer": "Tutankhamun"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Greek dramatist wrote the famous tragedy “Oedipus Rex”?",
            "answer": "Sophocles"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Greek mathematician used the method of exhaustion to calculate the area of a circle?",
            "answer": "Archimedes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Greek philosopher put forth the first ideas of atomism?",
            "answer": "Democritus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ancient Greek physicist famously discovered the concept of buoyancy while taking a bath?",
            "answer": "Archimedes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Greek scholar laid the foundation for future European mathematics and authored the “Elements” of geometry?",
            "answer": "Euclid"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which animal is featured on commander Richard I’s background image?",
            "answer": "A dog"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which art group is known as a “national treasure” of Canada?",
            "answer": "Cirque du Soleil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which artist painted the world-famous “Girl with a Pearl Earring”?",
            "answer": "Johannes Vermeer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which artist shocked the world by shredding a copy of his own work, Girl with Balloon, at an auction?",
            "answer": "Banksy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which astronomer proposed the heliocentric theory in the 16th century?",
            "answer": "Nicolaus Copernicus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which beverage was invented by American pharmacist John Pemberton?",
            "answer": "Cola"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which British star performed at the opening ceremony of the 2018 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Robbie Williams"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which buff can be acquired from occupying a Sanctum of Courage?",
            "answer": "Increase EXP gained by commanders"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which building was originally built in London to house the Great Exhibition of the Works of Industry of All Nations held in 1851?",
            "answer": "The Crystal Palace"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain comes from Horn Bay?",
            "answer": "Keira"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain comes from Sabertooth Valley?",
            "answer": "Ak & Hok"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain dual wields a dagger and bow?",
            "answer": "Wafura"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain dwells in a place known as Death Forest?",
            "answer": "Dekar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain has been tasked with safeguarding Windrage Cliffs?",
            "answer": "Astrid"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain has power over frost?",
            "answer": "Frida"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain once encircled the Citadel of Braves with their forces?",
            "answer": "Torgny"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain safeguards the Whitestone Tower?",
            "answer": "Frida"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain spent over 20 years garrisoning the Northern Reaches?",
            "answer": "Torgny"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain uses a bow for a weapon?",
            "answer": "Keira"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain wields two weapons at once?",
            "answer": "Astrid"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain works alongside a snake?",
            "answer": "Dekar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Ceroli Chieftain’s tribe has lived in the freezing wastes for generations?",
            "answer": "Wafura"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which chapter of the Kingdom Chronicles grants the “Explorer for Life” achievement if all mist is explored before the chapter’s end?",
            "answer": "Long Peace"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Chieftain from the Ceroli Crisis event is well-versed in poison magic?",
            "answer": "Dekar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Chieftain in the Ceroli Crisis event mounted a successful coup?",
            "answer": "Torgny"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Chinese dynasty did Jiang Ziya help to establish?",
            "answer": "The Zhou Dynasty"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which city hosted the 2000 Summer Olympics?",
            "answer": "Sydney"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which city-state defeated Sparta in the “Battle of Leuctra”?",
            "answer": "Thebes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which city-state of Ancient Greece was known for its brutal military training and bravery?",
            "answer": "Sparta"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which civilian airport is the highest above sea level?",
            "answer": "Daocheng Yading Airport"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which civilization was the first to have public toilets?",
            "answer": "Ancient Rome"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which club has footballer Lionel Messi played for the longest?",
            "answer": "Barcelona"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which club has won the most English Premier League titles?",
            "answer": "Manchester United"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander can be said to have the thickest eyebrows in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "Cao Cao"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander does NOT receive a skill level boost from a Legendary Commander Sculpture?",
            "answer": "Hannibal Barca"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander features a ship in their background image?",
            "answer": "Pelagius"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander has a crown with gemstones of a different color to the others?",
            "answer": "Queen Tamar of Georgia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is commonly regarded as having exemplified the ideal of the “Bushido Spirit”?",
            "answer": "Kusunoki Masashige"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is known as “The Immortal Hammer”?",
            "answer": "Charles Martel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is known as Barbarossa?",
            "answer": "Frederick I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is known as Kamakura’s Warlord?",
            "answer": "Minamoto no Yoshitsune"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is known as the Conqueror of Chaos?",
            "answer": "Cao Cao"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is known as the Lady of the Mercians?",
            "answer": "Æthelflæd"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is nicknamed “Bow of Revolution”?",
            "answer": "Yi Seong-Gye"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is nicknamed Carthage’s Guardian?",
            "answer": "Hannibal Barca"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is nicknamed the Father of Conquest?",
            "answer": "Baibars"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is nicknamed the Roaring Barbarian?",
            "answer": "Lohar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is reputed to have said, “I came, I saw, I conquered”?",
            "answer": "Julius Caesar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander role provides a load boost to troops?",
            "answer": "Supply Captain"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander says: “My destiny is determined by faith and opportunity”?",
            "answer": "Matilda of Flanders"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander showed their military genius in the Battle of Tours in the 8th century AD?",
            "answer": "Charles Martel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander signed a peace treaty with Saladin in 1192?",
            "answer": "Richard I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander was considered an enemy of Rome from an early age?",
            "answer": "Hannibal Barca"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander was in charge of capturing Constantinople at the age of 21?",
            "answer": "Mehmed II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander was known as the Celtic Rose?",
            "answer": "Boudica"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander was paired with Minamoto?",
            "answer": "Tomoe Gozen"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander wields the Beauty and Wisdom skill?",
            "answer": "Cleopatra VII"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Commander’s active skill can inflict Silence?",
            "answer": "Hermann"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which composer wrote the incidental music for the play “Peer Gynt”?",
            "answer": "Edvard Grieg"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which composer wrote the opera “The Ring of the Nibelung”?",
            "answer": "Wagner"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which continent has the lowest average temperatures?",
            "answer": "Antarctica"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which continent was the birthplace of Mayan civilization?",
            "answer": "The Americas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which continent was the Inca Empire located on?",
            "answer": "South America"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country did Arjen Robben play for?",
            "answer": "The Netherlands"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country did the famous poet Dante Alighieri come from?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country did Zarathustra, of the tone poem ‘Thus Spoke Zarathustra’, come from?",
            "answer": "Persia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country gave the Statue of Liberty to the American people as a gift?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country has adopted the quetzal as its national bird?",
            "answer": "Guatemala"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country has participated in 8 World Cups but has never advanced past the group stage?",
            "answer": "Scotland"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country has topped the FIFA world rankings but has never won a World Cup?",
            "answer": "Belgium"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country has won the most World Cups?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country has won the World Cup five times?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country hosted and won the 1930 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Uruguay"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country hosted and won the 1978 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Argentina"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country hosted the 1994 World Cup?",
            "answer": "The United States"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country hosted the 1998 World Cup?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country hosted the 2022 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Qatar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country hosted the first ever Winter Olympics on January 25, 1924?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country hosted the first World Cup?",
            "answer": "Uruguay"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country is Çatalhöyük located in?",
            "answer": "Turkey"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country is responsible for inventing blue cheese, well-known for its pungent taste?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country used an orange as its World Cup mascot?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country was allowed to keep the Jules Rimet Trophy permanently?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country was England fighting against in the Battle of Agincourt?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country was Marco Polo, a famous explorer and merchant, born in?",
            "answer": "Republic of Venice"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country was the composer Franz Schubert from?",
            "answer": "Austria"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country was the first Asian country to reach the semi-final stage of the World Cup?",
            "answer": "Korea"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country was the first to invent perfume?",
            "answer": "Cyprus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country won the 2018 World Cup held in Russia?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country’s explorers were the first to land in Antarctica?",
            "answer": "Norway"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country’s team has played in every World Cup?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which creature decoration from Greek mythology can governors construct in their city?",
            "answer": "Pegasus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which deity of ancient Egyptian mythology was represented by the obelisk?",
            "answer": "Ra"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which demigod captures Cerberus, the “three-headed hound of Hades”, according to Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Hercules"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Dutch scientist is known as “the father of microbiology”?",
            "answer": "Antonie van Leeuwenhoek"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which emperor issued the Edict of Milan?",
            "answer": "Constantine I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Egyptian city marked the boundary between Upper Egypt and Lower Egypt during the pre-dynastic period?",
            "answer": "Memphis"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which emperor issued the Proclamation of Milan?",
            "answer": "Constantine I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which emperor was named the “Khan of Heaven” by various Turkic nomads during the Sui and Tang dynasties?",
            "answer": "Emperor Taizong of Tang"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which entomologist and astronomer from New Zealand first proposed adopting a method of Daylight Saving Time?",
            "answer": "George Hudson"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ethnic group founded the earliest civilization of Mesopotamia?",
            "answer": "The Sumerians"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which European country’s king funded Christopher Columbus’ famous expedition?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which European wrote the first travelogue detailing China’s history, culture, and art?",
            "answer": "Marco Polo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which famous and influential family did the famous Renaissance art patron Duke Lorenzo belong to?",
            "answer": "The House of Medici"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which famous Japanese samurai was called “Ushiwakamaru” as a child?",
            "answer": "Minamoto no Yoshitsune"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which famous sculpture features a child urinating?",
            "answer": "Manneken Pis"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which figure from Greek mythology did Mary Shelley associate Frankenstein’s monster with?",
            "answer": "Prometheus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which figure of history disguised himself as a Prussian captain and made off with over 4000 gold marks only to be later regarded as a folk hero and called the “Captain of Köpenick”?",
            "answer": "Wilhelm Voigt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which film won Outstanding Picture at the first ever Oscars?",
            "answer": "Wings"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which flavor of soup can does NOT appear in Andy Warhol’s famous work titled “Campbell’s Soup Cans”?",
            "answer": "Corn"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which formation is the “Imperial War Drum” armament for?",
            "answer": "V"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which French monarch was known as “Saint Louis”?",
            "answer": "Louis IX"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Futhark rune represents Týr, the god of war and justice in Germanic mythology?",
            "answer": "Tiwaz"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which gas makes up more than 90% of Mars’ atmosphere?",
            "answer": "Carbon Dioxide"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which German psychologist discovered the human brain’s forgetting curve?",
            "answer": "Hermann Ebbinghaus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which goalkeeper has scored the most goals in professional soccer?",
            "answer": "Rogério Ceni"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which god is Taranis in Celtic mythology?",
            "answer": "Thunder God"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Greek goddess is portrayed on the Jules Rimet trophy, the original World Cup trophy?",
            "answer": "Nike"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which inventor built the world’s first electric locomotive in 1837?",
            "answer": "Robert Davidson"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is Minamoto no Yoshitsune’s active skill?",
            "answer": "Kyohachiryu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is recognized by the Guinness Book of World Records as having the largest cumulative circulation of any single-author comic?",
            "answer": "One Piece"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the deepest known trench in the world?",
            "answer": "The Mariana Trench"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the highest plateau in the world?",
            "answer": "The Tibetan Plateau"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the longest continental mountain range on earth?",
            "answer": "The Andes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the smallest known snake species?",
            "answer": "Barbados threadsnake"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the Viking civilization’s special unit?",
            "answer": "Berserker"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the world’s largest church?",
            "answer": "St. Peter’s Basilica"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the world’s smallest island country?",
            "answer": "Nauru"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Italian city is known as the “Queen of the Adriatic”",
            "answer": "Venice"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Japanese haiku poet wrote under the pseudonym “Tosei”?",
            "answer": "Matsuo Basho"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which kingdom did the commander Boudica reign over?",
            "answer": "Iceni"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which landmark in Sydney, Australia is shaped like sails?",
            "answer": "Sydney Opera House"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which mammalian order does Suidae belong to?",
            "answer": "Artiodactyla"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which manager has managed in six World Cups?",
            "answer": "Carlos Alberto Parreira"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which manager led his team to a record 11 consecutive World Cup match victories?",
            "answer": "Luiz Felipe Scolari"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which military commander was known as the “Teutoburg’s Liberator”?",
            "answer": "Hermann"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which military leader was known as the “Reformer of the Legions”?",
            "answer": "Gaius Marius"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which modern-day city was Shakespeare’s Globe Theater built in?",
            "answer": "London"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which monarch built the Hagia Sophia?",
            "answer": "Justinian I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which musical instrument is a national emblem of Ireland?",
            "answer": "Harp"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which musician composed “The Marriage of Figaro”?",
            "answer": "Mozart"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which new method of constructing columns in ancient Rome was based on the three main Greek styles?",
            "answer": "The Tuscan column."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Nobel Prize is the most recently established?",
            "answer": "The Nobel Prize in Economics"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of Saturn’s rings is outside of Saturn’s Roche limit?",
            "answer": "E Ring"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the Babylonian Codes of Law was the first full set of written laws in recorded history?",
            "answer": "The Code of Hammurabi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the below figures were not Knights of King Arthur’s Round Table?",
            "answer": "Merlin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the below states was not part of the Three Kingdoms period?",
            "answer": "Jin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following accurately describes the Arctic Circle?",
            "answer": "Polar Day and Polar Night are phenomenons that occur there"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following achievements must be completed before the “Special Snowflake” achievement?",
            "answer": "Long-range Strike"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following actions is NOT available to an alliance leader in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "Quit Alliance"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following animals does NOT lay eggs?",
            "answer": "Bat"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following animals is an amphibian?",
            "answer": "Frog"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following animals is NOT extinct?",
            "answer": "Giant panda"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following animals is NOT real?",
            "answer": "Dragon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following animals was on the imperial banner of the Inca Empire?",
            "answer": "Snake"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following are carnivores?",
            "answer": "Dragonflies"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following are NOT mammals?",
            "answer": "Turtle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following awards daily activity points?",
            "answer": "Defeating barbarian troops on the map"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following best describes a Clownfish?",
            "answer": "Tropical marine fish"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following buffs can take effect during Sunset Canyon battles?",
            "answer": "Buffs from equipment"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following buffs comes from levelling up the required structure to level 25?",
            "answer": "Transportation March Speed Bonus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following buildings cannot be upgraded?",
            "answer": "Courier Station"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following buildings was NOT the work of the architect Antoni Gaudi?",
            "answer": "Florence Cathedral"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following can NOT be found in a Silver Chest at the Tavern?",
            "answer": "Lv.3 Tome of Knowledge"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following can NOT be found in Alliance Shops?",
            "answer": "Golden Key"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following CANNOT be equipped to a Commander?",
            "answer": "Lohar’s Longbow"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following cat breeds is known for being hairless?",
            "answer": "Sphynx"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following characters are NOT present in the “Journey to the West” story?",
            "answer": "Third Sister Hu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following cheeses is classified as a hard cheese?",
            "answer": "Parmesan"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following Chinese emperors’ reigns was known as the “Reign of Zhenguan”?",
            "answer": "Emperor Taizong of Tang"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following cities is the capital of France?",
            "answer": "Paris"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following cities was the first to have an underground rapid transit system?",
            "answer": "London"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following city buildings CAN be upgraded?",
            "answer": "Trading Post"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following civilizations cannot buff their cavalry?",
            "answer": "The Ottomans"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following civilizations give a 5% attack bonus to cavalry units?",
            "answer": "Germany"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following civilizations gives a 20% healing speed bonus to hospitals?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following civilizations increases the damage of active commander skills by 5%?",
            "answer": "Ottomans"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following civilizations provides a building speed boost?",
            "answer": "China"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders excels at attacking enemy cities?",
            "answer": "Julius Caesar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders excels at gathering resources?",
            "answer": "Cleopatra VII"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders excels at leading archers?",
            "answer": "Yi Seong-Gye"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders excels at leading cavalry?",
            "answer": "Minamoto no Yoshitsune"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders excels at leading infantry?",
            "answer": "Richard I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders in RoK was the only ruler in history to defeat Cyrus the Great in a major battle?",
            "answer": "Tomyris"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders joined a rebellion against her own husband?",
            "answer": "Constance"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders was effectively the ruler of their kingdom, but never officially the head of state?",
            "answer": "Charles Martel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders was part of the Battle of Red Cliffs?",
            "answer": "Cao Cao"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders was part of the Hundred Years’ War?",
            "answer": "Joan of Arc"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders’ sculptures cannot be donated to the “Past Glory” event after the Lost Kingdom has been opened?",
            "answer": "Æthelflæd"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following constellations is shaped like a crown?",
            "answer": "Corona Borealis"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following countries is located entirely in the Northern Hemisphere?",
            "answer": "None of these answers are correct"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following countries is located in the northern hemisphere?",
            "answer": "United Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following countries or regions is NOT part of Northern Europe?",
            "answer": "Argentina"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following courses are you most likely to take in law school?",
            "answer": "Intro to Criminal Law"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following deities were NOT meant to be given offerings at the Abu Simbel Temples?",
            "answer": "Anubis"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following describes a monotheist?",
            "answer": "Someone who warships 1 god"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following descriptions of microscopes is false?",
            "answer": "They can be used to observe stars"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following did NOT occur during the Greco-Persian Wars?",
            "answer": "The Battle of Agincourt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following doctors was the first to describe completely, and in detail, the systemic circulation and the function of the heart?",
            "answer": "William Harvey"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following does not award Individual Credits?",
            "answer": "Giving resources to allies"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following does NOT give Commanders EXP?",
            "answer": "Attacking other players"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following does NOT increase an Alliance’s member limit?",
            "answer": "Appointing officers"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following events occurred AFTER the 19th century?",
            "answer": "The release of Rise of Kingdoms"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following events took place in North America during the Roaring Twenties?",
            "answer": "The “Weird Tales” magazine was first published"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following films was scored by the Japanese composer Ryuichi Sakamoto?",
            "answer": "The Revenant"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following fish lures its prey through bioluminescence?",
            "answer": "Anglerfish"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following French Kings was known as the Sun King?",
            "answer": "Louis XIV"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following fruits, know as “wolf peach”, were erroneously thought to be poisonous?",
            "answer": "Tomatoes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following fruits does NOT grow on trees?",
            "answer": "Strawberries"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following historical figures never engaged in medical work?",
            "answer": "Justinian"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following illnesses can be caused by a lack of Vitamin D?",
            "answer": "Rickets"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following inventions did NOT come about during the first industrial Revolution?",
            "answer": "The telephone"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a ball game?",
            "answer": "Soccer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a decorative building?",
            "answer": "Stone Drum"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a fossil fuel formed from marine organisms that is often found in folded or tilted layers and used for heating and cooking?",
            "answer": "Natural gas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a liquid fossil fuel formed from marine organisms that is burned to obtain energy and used to manufacture plastics?",
            "answer": "Oil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a military building?",
            "answer": "Scout Camp"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a name for sedimentary rock formed from decayed plant material in swampy areas?",
            "answer": "Coal"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a phase of The Mightiest Governor event?",
            "answer": "Enemy Elimination"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a prime number?",
            "answer": "29"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an alternative energy source based on splitting heavy atoms into lighter ones to release energy?",
            "answer": "Nuclear energy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an economic building?",
            "answer": "Alliance Center"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is an inexhaustible energy resource that relies on hot magma or hot, dry rocks below ground?",
            "answer": "Geothermal energy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is another name for the “Black Death” that raged across the Europe during the Late Middle Ages?",
            "answer": "Yersinia pestis"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is considered a metallic resource?",
            "answer": "Iron"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is considered one of Confucius’ disciples?",
            "answer": "Yan Hui"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is extinct?",
            "answer": "The Steller’s Sea Cow"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a “cold weapon”?",
            "answer": "Handgun"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a “low country” of Europe?",
            "answer": "The United Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a ball game?",
            "answer": "Fencing"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a benefit of upgrading your Tavern?",
            "answer": "Improves the variety of rewards in Golden Chests"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a Champions of Olympia map?",
            "answer": "Treasure Hill"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of Renaissance art?",
            "answer": "Flat/Two-dimensional"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the followign is not a common Chinese New Year tradition?",
            "answer": "Eating mooncakes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a component ingredient used to forge the Epic weapon “Golden Age”?",
            "answer": "Animal Bone"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a King skill?",
            "answer": "Relief"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a natural resource?",
            "answer": "Clothing"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a noble gas?",
            "answer": "Oxygen"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a part of a typical human respiratory system?",
            "answer": "Impact wrench"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a prerequisite for the Military Technology Cartography?",
            "answer": "Ballistics"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a reason why the Renaissance began in Italy?",
            "answer": "The Black Plague did not hit Italy as a result of the Alps"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a suit in poker?",
            "answer": "Winds"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a type of dance?",
            "answer": "Sumo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT an accurate description of the “Manila galleons”?",
            "answer": "They were used for enemy reconnaissance"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT an accurate description of the ancient Kingdom of Kush?",
            "answer": "It did not possess its own unique language and script"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not an objective of Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Provide a path for salvation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT considered a single-celled organism?",
            "answer": "Mites"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Belisarius’ skills?",
            "answer": "Thunderous Force"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of El Cid’s skills?",
            "answer": "Chivalry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Hermann’s skills?",
            "answer": "Irresistible"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Julius Caesar’s skills?",
            "answer": "Military Life"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Keira’s skills?",
            "answer": "Unruly Blood"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Lohar’s skills?",
            "answer": "Utter Annihilation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Matilda of Flanders’ skills?",
            "answer": "Celtic Blood"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Mulan’s skills?",
            "answer": "Indomitable Army"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Osman I’s skills",
            "answer": "Oblique Tactics"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Pelagius’ passive skills?",
            "answer": "Charge"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not one of the Fates of Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Urd"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not one of the Fates of Norse mythology?",
            "answer": "Karma"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the major greenhouse gases in earth’s atmosphere?",
            "answer": "Nitrogen"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT part of Mexico’s flag?",
            "answer": "Camel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is the correct description for the stratosphere?",
            "answer": "It is warm above and cold below"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is the second largest river delta in Europe?",
            "answer": "Danube Delta"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is the world’s first national park?",
            "answer": "Yellowstone National Park"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is the world’s largest island?",
            "answer": "Greenland"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is Zeus’ elder brother in Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Poseidon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following items can be used to upgrade a commander’s skills?",
            "answer": "Commander Sculptures"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following juice is contained in the classic cocktail “Bloody Mary”?",
            "answer": "Tomato Juice"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following kingdom title descriptions is incorrect?",
            "answer": "Dukes’ troops have increased attack"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following laureates won a Nobel Prize in two different fields?",
            "answer": "Marie Curie"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following managers has led his team to 13 English Premier League titles?",
            "answer": "Alex Ferguson"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following marine species has existed the longest?",
            "answer": "Nautilus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following mountains is under 8000 meters tall?",
            "answer": "Chomo Lonzo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following musical instruments has six strings?",
            "answer": "Guitar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following nations is the closest to the North Pole?",
            "answer": "Finland"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following organs is part of the human respiratory system?",
            "answer": "Lungs"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following penalties may be applied in response to the use of third-party software?",
            "answer": "Battle restrictions"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following physicists was born on the death anniversary of Galileo Galilei, and died on the birth anniversary of Albert Einstein?",
            "answer": "Stephen Hawking"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following plants has been disputed as a fruit or vegetable?",
            "answer": "Tomato"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following plants is visible in Mulan and Cao Cao’s background image on the commander screen?",
            "answer": "Bamboo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following regions is the primary habitat of polar bears?",
            "answer": "Arctic Circle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following resources cannot be found in your jeans?",
            "answer": "Lead"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following rewards CANNOT be obtained from a Barbarian Keep in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "Commander Sculptures"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following rulers was a member of the Varangian Guard?",
            "answer": "Harald Hardrada"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following serves as the national flower of the Philippines?",
            "answer": "Sampaguita"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following Shakespeare plays is a romantic comedy written some time between 1590 and 1596?",
            "answer": "A Midsummer Night’s Dream"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following soccer clubs is NOT based in London?",
            "answer": "Everton"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following speeches was made by the Prussian prime Minister Otto von Bismarck in September of 1862?",
            "answer": "Blood and Iron"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following Speedups are NOT available in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "6-Hour Speedup"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements about the Battle of Baideng is untrue?",
            "answer": "It was a battle between the Tang dynasty and the Xiongnu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements about the tango is FALSE?",
            "answer": "It was created in the 15th century"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements about Zhuge Liang in RoK is INCORRECT?",
            "answer": "He excels at leading cavalry units"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following statements is a 6-month-old human baby most likely to make?",
            "answer": "“Mama”"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following stories not included in “One Thousand and One Nights”?",
            "answer": "Layla and Majnun"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following stories is not one of Grimms’ Fairy Tales?",
            "answer": "The Little Mermaid"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following straits is located between Eurasia and North America?",
            "answer": "The Bering Strait"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following teams has won the most FIFA World Cup titles?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following technologies precedes “Horsemanship”?",
            "answer": "Military Discipline"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following titles can only be used by an Islamic ruler?",
            "answer": "Sultan"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following trees is commonly found in boreal ecosystems?",
            "answer": "Spruce"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following types of bonuses do NOT take effect in Ark of Osiris?",
            "answer": "Rune buffs"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following units of measurement is NOT used for measuring ionizing radiation?",
            "answer": "Lumens"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following vitamins is most helpful for maintaining good vision?",
            "answer": "Vitamin A"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was a general during Japan’s Genpei War?",
            "answer": "Tomoe Gozen"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was a Knight of the Round Table?",
            "answer": "Lancelot"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was a Renaissance intellectual movement in which thinkers studied classical texts and focused on human potential and achievements?",
            "answer": "Humanism"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was also known as the Eastern Roman Empire?",
            "answer": "The Byzantine Empire"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was an enemy of Richard the Lionheart?",
            "answer": "Saladin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was built at the order of Shah Jahan in the memory of his wife Mumtaz Mahal?",
            "answer": "The Taj Mahal"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was not a pillar of the Renaissance?",
            "answer": "Mannerism"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was NOT essential for a Vizier, the Pharaoh’s most senior civil servant, in ancient Egypt?",
            "answer": "To have royal blood"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was NOT included in the first Summer Olympics, held in Athens in 1896?",
            "answer": "Basketball"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was praised by his countrymen as Ancient Greece’s best and most honest democratic representatives?",
            "answer": "Pericles"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was the highest-ranked medal in the Korean Empire?",
            "answer": "Order of the Gold Cheok"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was written by Mary Shelley?",
            "answer": "Frankenstein"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following were born in the same year as singer Luciano Pavarotti?",
            "answer": "Elvis Presley"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following will NOT prevent you from entering an Ark of Osiris Battlefield?",
            "answer": "Activating an Attack Enhancement"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following works is based on the Battle of Roncevaux Pass, fought by Charlemagne and his knights?",
            "answer": "“The Song of Roland”"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following works was NOT written by the musical maestro Andrew Lloyd Webber?",
            "answer": "Les Misérables"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following works was written by the French playwright Pierre Corneille?",
            "answer": "Le Cid"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following works was written by Victor Hugo?",
            "answer": "The Hunchback of Notre-Dame"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the scientific bird names was also used to commemorate the wife of Napoleon III, the Empress of France, Eugénie de Montijo?",
            "answer": "The white-headed fruit dove"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the seven wonders of the world were created to cure the new Queen of Babylon’s homesickness?",
            "answer": "The Hanging Gardens"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these achievements is earned from healing 100,000 injured troops in the hospital?",
            "answer": "Rebuilding"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these actions can be performed by alliance leaders and titled officers, but NOT non-titled officers?",
            "answer": "Sign up for Ark of Osiris"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these active skills belongs to Charles Martel?",
            "answer": "Immortal Shield"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these airports has runways on a beach?",
            "answer": "Barra Airport"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these alliance officers bestows a Research Speed boost?",
            "answer": "Counselor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Alliance Skills increases damage versus barbarians and other neutral units?",
            "answer": "Unbridled Progress"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Alliance Skills will boost your resource gathering speed?",
            "answer": "Fully Loaded"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these ancient Greek dramatists is regarded as “the father of tragedy”?",
            "answer": "Aeschylus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these ancient Greek philosophers did NOT participate in the discussion on justice in Plato’s Republic?",
            "answer": "Protagoras"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these ancient Greek writers is regard as “the father of comedy”?",
            "answer": "Aristophanes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these animals is NOT a rodent?",
            "answer": "Monkey"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these animated movies was NOT directed by Hayao Miyazaki?",
            "answer": "Paprika"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these are invertebrates?",
            "answer": "Coral"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these areas contains a waterwheel?",
            "answer": "Alliance Cropland"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these artists was NOT a Baroque painter?",
            "answer": "Vincent van Gogh"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these authors created the character Eugene Onegin?",
            "answer": "Alexander Pushkin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Avatar Frames are available for purchase?",
            "answer": "Rose Petals"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Avatar Frames can be obtained from the Ceroli Crisis event?",
            "answer": "Undersea Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Blessings immediately inflicts a 10% loss of troop power on your enemy at the start of battle in the “Golden Kingdom” event?",
            "answer": "Anchor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these books was not written by the Greek philosopher Aristotle?",
            "answer": "Republic"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these boosts work in Expeditions in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "All of them"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these boosts work in Sunset Canyon?",
            "answer": "VIP Level troop capacity"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these buildings is NOT one of the New Seven Wonders of the World?",
            "answer": "The Palace of Versailles"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Byzantine emperors ruled alongside four other emperors at various times only later to be declared Rome’s sole emperor after 63 years in power?",
            "answer": "Constantine VIII"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Ceroli Chieftains is also called Stormbringer?",
            "answer": "Torgny"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Ceroli Chieftains is also called the Disaster Bringer?",
            "answer": "Dekar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these characters is from “Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Seas”?",
            "answer": "Captain Nemo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Chinese ethnic groups is known for drinking kumis, a drink made from fermented mare’s milk?",
            "answer": "Mongols"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these circumstances would prevent you from changing civilization?",
            "answer": "Ongoing troop training in your city"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these cities hosted the Olympics in 1900?",
            "answer": "Paris"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these cities in Brazil has hosted the Olympic Games?",
            "answer": "Rio de Janeiro"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these cities is located in South America?",
            "answer": "Buenos Aires"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these cities is NOT in Asia?",
            "answer": "Melbourne"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these city themes feature balloons?",
            "answer": "Harvest Cottage"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these City Themes offers a special attributes bonus of +5% to Cavalry Attack and -5% to Archer Health?",
            "answer": "Sower’s Song"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these civilizations can increase Archer Defense?",
            "answer": "Korea"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these civilizations can increase their healing speed?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these civilizations can increase their Hospital Capacity?",
            "answer": "Byzantium"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these civilizations used a hieroglyphic writing system?",
            "answer": "Ancient Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders carries a bow and arrows as well as a sword?",
            "answer": "Æthelflæd"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders does NOT carry a shield?",
            "answer": "Charlemagne"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders does NOT carry a sword?",
            "answer": "Theodora"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders features snowflakes in their background image?",
            "answer": "Björn Ironside"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Commanders gets the ability to convert some slain units into severely wounded units when attacking a city?",
            "answer": "Charlemagne"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders has also been called a “Holy Overlord”?",
            "answer": "El Cid"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders has an Attack branch on their Talent tree?",
            "answer": "Centurion"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders has NO whiskers or other facial hair?",
            "answer": "Alexander the Great"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders has the Enchantment active skill?",
            "answer": "Šárka"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders is bald?",
            "answer": "Ragnar Lodbrok"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders is NOT shown wearing a cloak?",
            "answer": "Mehmed II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders is often described as having survived 57 engagements without a single defeat?",
            "answer": "Honda Tadakatsu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders wears a ring on their hand?",
            "answer": "Queen Tamar of Georgia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders will gain a bonus from the Museum Relic “Twin Dragons Inscription”?",
            "answer": "Yi Seong-Gye"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders’ Expertise Skill is the enhanced version of an existing skill?",
            "answer": "Björn Ironside"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders’ sculptures can be obtained from opening a chest in the Tavern in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "Charles Martel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these consonants is trilled when pronounced in Italian?",
            "answer": "r"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these countries did NOT participate in the Northern Seven Years’ War (1563-1570)?",
            "answer": "The United Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these countries does the Prime Meridian pass through?",
            "answer": "Mali"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these countries has had the most influence on the development of Cuban food?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these countries was NOT a founding member of NATO (in 1949)?",
            "answer": "Turkey"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these countries’ flags contains the greatest number of colors?",
            "answer": "Republic of Korea"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these creatures was also popularly used as a kind of personal protective talisman in ancient Egypt?",
            "answer": "Scarabs"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these decorations does NOT cost Gems?",
            "answer": "Sakura Tree"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these decorative buildings is also considered an omen of good luck in Chinese culture?",
            "answer": "Chinese Dragon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these effects is NOT caused by Æthelflæd’s skills?",
            "answer": "Healing slightly wounded units"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these events is NOT part of the Olympic Games?",
            "answer": "Car racing"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these female commanders has been described as “The Georgian Will”?",
            "answer": "Queen Tamar of Georgia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these female commanders has flowers in their hair?",
            "answer": "Boudica"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these fields is NOT included in the list of Nobel Prizes?",
            "answer": "Mathematics"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these figures of the Seleucid Empire was taken hostage by Rome, subsequently fled Rome, and then returned to seize the throne of their home country?",
            "answer": "Demetrius I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these films was NOT directed by Peter Weir?",
            "answer": "Detachment"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these foods could the Eastern Han statesman Cao Cao not have eaten?",
            "answer": "Corn"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these fruits appears in the background image for the Commander Imhotep?",
            "answer": "Banana"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these gods of ancient Egypt was also a symbol of royal authority?",
            "answer": "Horus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these historical figures was NOT a botanist?",
            "answer": "Dmitry Mendeleev"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these holy sites grants a march speed bonus?",
            "answer": "Sanctum of Wind"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these ingredients is used to brew soy sauce?",
            "answer": "Soybeans"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is a line of Tomoe Gozen?",
            "answer": "My power scares even the ghosts."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is a passive skill of Commander Thutmose III?",
            "answer": "Conquest of Mitanni"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is an incorrect description of the “Battle of Poitiers”?",
            "answer": "The campaign took place during World War I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is an incorrect description of the “Mare Imbrium” on the moon?",
            "answer": "It contains a certain amount of sedimentary water"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is an incorrect description of wind energy?",
            "answer": "It is not a form of renewable energy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is considered to be the seminal work of the French playwright Molière?",
            "answer": "Tartuffe"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is found in the alliance Golden Chest?",
            "answer": "1,000 Individual Credits"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT a breakdown of alliance technology?",
            "answer": "Military"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT a mail report category?",
            "answer": "Gathering"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT a passive skill of Commander Minamoto no Yoshitsune?",
            "answer": "The Worthy Man"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is not a skill of the Ceroli general Keira?",
            "answer": "The Red Chameleon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT a type of Japanese wagyu",
            "answer": "Ronguhon Wagyu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT a typical stage of sewage treatment?",
            "answer": "Discharge"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT an Alliance Skill?",
            "answer": "Rapid March"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is not an ancient civilization of the Americas?",
            "answer": "The Sumerians"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is not an official song of the 2022 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Tatu Bom de Bola"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT considered a Shakespearean tragedy?",
            "answer": "Twelfth Night"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT considered one of the “Five Good Emperors” of the Nerva-Antonine dynasty of ancient Rome?",
            "answer": "Commodus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT considered one of the 8 main styles of contemporary Chinese cooking?",
            "answer": "Huaiyang Cuisine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT one of Cao Cao’s skills?",
            "answer": "Battle of Sorrow"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT one of the skills of Ceroli Chieftain Astrid?",
            "answer": "Flametongue’s Kiss"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is not one of the Three Gorgon Sisters of Grecian myth?",
            "answer": "Perga"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT one of the Winning Stratagems listed in the ancient Chinese military textbook, the “Thirty-Six Stratagems”?",
            "answer": "The “empty fort” strategy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is not part of the Holy Trinity in Christianity?",
            "answer": "The Mother"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT Zeus’ child in Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Hera"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is one of Diaochan’s Active Skills?",
            "answer": "Dance of Chaos"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is one of Minamoto no Yoshitsune’s “Active Skills”?",
            "answer": "Kyohachiryu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is one of the four fundamental elements of nature according to many ancient Greek philosophers?",
            "answer": "Wind"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is the most visited art museum in the world in recent years?",
            "answer": "The Louvre"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is the National Flower of India?",
            "answer": "Lotus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is used to rally Alliance troops?",
            "answer": "Castle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is Yi Seong-Gye an expert in?",
            "answer": "Garrisoning"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these islands is considered the birthplace of Minoan civilization?",
            "answer": "Crete"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these items can NOT be obtained by defeating barbarians?",
            "answer": "VIP points"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these items can NOT be purchased within the Mysterious Merchant’s Boutique?",
            "answer": "Passport Page"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these items CANNOT be obtained from a Tavern Equipment Chest?",
            "answer": "60-Minute Training Speedup"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these items cannot be obtained from an Equipment Chest?",
            "answer": "Tomes of Knowledge"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these items CANNOT be obtained from the Alliance Stone Chest?",
            "answer": "Silver Keys"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these items contains a helpful record on how an ancient Egyptian can pass into the next world after death?",
            "answer": "The Book of the Dead"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these items may be selected from the Lvl 3 “Pick One” Resource Chest?",
            "answer": "150,000 Food"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these legendary phrases are NOT attributed to Commander El Cid?",
            "answer": "For honor and empire!"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these managers has managed five World Cup teams?",
            "answer": "Bora Milutinović"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these materials is used to forge gathering and peacekeeping equipment?",
            "answer": "Animal Bone"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these modern-day countries is NOT located in the historical territory of the Maya civilization?",
            "answer": "Dominican Republic"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these navigators was the first European to arrive in Brazil?",
            "answer": "Pedro Álvares Cabral"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Nobel Prizes was awarded to Marie Curie in 1903?",
            "answer": "The Nobel Prize in Physics"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these novels is the first ever Japanese work of literary fiction founded on the legend of King Arthur?",
            "answer": "Kairo-kō"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these novels was NOT written by Margaret Atwood?",
            "answer": "Flowers for Algernon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these numbers is NOT in the Fibonacci sequence?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these organizations has its headquarters in Geneva?",
            "answer": "UN High Commissioner for Refugees"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these people did not win a Nobel Prize in Physics in 2022?",
            "answer": "Karl Barry Sharpless"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these philosophers was not an advocate of the Cynicism school of philosophy?",
            "answer": "Socrates"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these plants is NOT available as a decorative building?",
            "answer": "Peach Tree"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these plays was not written by the ancient Greek tragedian Euripides?",
            "answer": "Antigone"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Polish pianists also served as the Prime Minister of Poland?",
            "answer": "Ignacy Jan Paderewski"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Renaissance-era artists was not from Italy?",
            "answer": "Shakespeare"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these rewards will NOT be awarded to the first place season finisher in Sunset Canyon?",
            "answer": "Dazzling Starlight Sculpture"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these rivers flows through Africa?",
            "answer": "The Nile"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these rivers is located in Asia?",
            "answer": "The Euphrates"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these RoK commanders is from Ceroli?",
            "answer": "Keira"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these sculptures was the work of the ancient Greek sculptor Pheidias?",
            "answer": "Statue of Zeus at Olympia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these skills belonging to Commander Sun Tzu is enhanced upon Awakening?",
            "answer": "Art of War"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these species of shark is also known as the “Godzilla shark”?",
            "answer": "Dracopristis hoffmanorum"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these stars did not take part in the 2022 World Cup opening ceremony?",
            "answer": "Shakira"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these structures allows scouts and City Defenders to better keep an eye on their surroundings?",
            "answer": "Watchtower"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these technologies can be researched in the Academy to accelerate food gathering on the map?",
            "answer": "Scythe"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these terms was also used by the ancient Egyptians to refer to themselves?",
            "answer": "The cattle of Ra"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these terrain types exerts a slight penalty on troop Defense on the Treasure Hill map in “Champions of Olympia”?",
            "answer": "Whirlwind"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these two were created by Leonardo da Vinci?",
            "answer": "The Last Supper, Mona Lisa"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these unfortunate individuals was the only person ever recorded to suffer from both dwarfism and gigantism?",
            "answer": "Adam Rainer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these was NOT a common type of garden in ancient Egypt?",
            "answer": "Public gardens"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these was NOT a Greek poet?",
            "answer": "Adonis"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these was the only commander to defeat Cyrus the Great in battle?",
            "answer": "Tomyris"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these was the world’s first space station?",
            "answer": "Salyut 1"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these women is NOT considered one of the ‘Four Beauties’ of ancient China?",
            "answer": "Bao Si"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these works is not set during the Trojan War?",
            "answer": "Antigone"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these works of Japanese Monogatari literature describes the legend of “Kaguya-hime”?",
            "answer": "The Tale of The Bamboo Cutter"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these works was NOT written by the philosopher Friedrich Nietzsche?",
            "answer": "Commentaries on the Gallic War"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these WOULD NOT be a penalty for failing to fully extract all resources from a resource point?",
            "answer": "Suffering a barbarian attack"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these writers is considered representative of absurdism?",
            "answer": "Albert Camus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which official measure made it a crime to give Martin Luther food or shelter?",
            "answer": "Edict of Worms"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which organ of the potato plant do we commonly eat?",
            "answer": "Stem"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Paris Saint-Germain player plays Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "Marquinhos"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which period of European history, lasting from 1300 to 1600, saw renewed interest in classical culture and led to far-reaching changes in art, learning, and views of the world?",
            "answer": "The Renaissance"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Pharaoh constructed the Bent Pyramid?",
            "answer": "Sneferu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Pharaoh issued the edict that appears on the Rosetta Stone?",
            "answer": "Ptolemy V"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Pharaoh ordered the construction of the Abu Simbel temples?",
            "answer": "Ramesses II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which philosopher coined the philosophical term “entelechy”?",
            "answer": "Aristotle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which philosopher said “whereof one cannot speak, thereof one must be silent”?",
            "answer": "Wittgenstein"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which philosopher wrote “Utopia”?",
            "answer": "Plato"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which planet in our solar system is closest to the sun?",
            "answer": "Mercury"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which planet in our solar system is most frequently in retrograde to Earth?",
            "answer": "Mercury"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which planet in our solar system rotates the fastest?",
            "answer": "Jupiter"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which poet wrote “Germany. A Winter’s Tale”?",
            "answer": "Heine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which poet wrote “Theogony”, which describes the origins and genealogy of the Greek gods?",
            "answer": "Hesiod"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Portuguese explorer sailed from the Cape of Good Hope to India?",
            "answer": "Vasco da Gama"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Portuguese explorer was the first European to sail to the southern tip of Africa?",
            "answer": "Bartolomeu Dias"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which privilege is reserved for titled officers (not normal officers)?",
            "answer": "The ability to check alliance members’ online status"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which prominent statesman served as the first general of the Edo shogunate at the end of Japan’s Warring States period?",
            "answer": "Tokugawa Ieyasu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which pyramid is widely considered the only surviving Wonder of the Ancient World still with us today?",
            "answer": "The Pyramid of Khufu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which rare animal does the WWF use as its logo?",
            "answer": "Panda"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Roman emperor defeated and captured Zenobia?",
            "answer": "Aurelian"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Roman Emperor was named Augustus after ending a civil war?",
            "answer": "Gaius Octavius"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which school of painting would Georges Seurat be a representative of?",
            "answer": "Pointillism"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which school of thought was founded by the Chinese philosopher Lao Tzu?",
            "answer": "Taoism"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which scout attribute CANNOT be enhanced by upgrading a Lvl 11 Scout Camp?",
            "answer": "Number of Scouts"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which script was the Code of Hammurabi engraved onto stone in?",
            "answer": "Cuneiform"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which sculpture was once described by Mark Twain as the “the most mournful and moving piece of stone in the world”?",
            "answer": "The Lion of Lucerne"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which solar term is closest to the 2024 Lunar New Year (February 10, 2024)?",
            "answer": "Lichun"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which star played in both the 1994 and 2010 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Rigobert Song"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which star was the oldest player to score a goal in the World Cup?",
            "answer": "Roger Milla"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which state created the earliest form of paper money?",
            "answer": "Ancient China"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which state is home to the Walt Disney Company?",
            "answer": "California"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which state was the first to invent and use papyrus as a writing material?",
            "answer": "Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which team has only played a single match in the World Cup?",
            "answer": "Indonesia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which team made their World Cup debut in 2022?",
            "answer": "Qatar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which team was the only former World Cup winner to fail to qualify for the 2022 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which team won 4th place in the 2018 World Cup?",
            "answer": "England"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which technology comes right before Heavy Cavalry?",
            "answer": "Scale Armor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which technology comes right before Pavise?",
            "answer": "Bodkin Arrows"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which technology comes right before Swordsman?",
            "answer": "Iron Working"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which three countries will host the 2026 World Cup?",
            "answer": "USA, Canada, and Mexico"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which title did Pierre de Coubertin, founder of the International Olympic Committee, hold?",
            "answer": "Baron"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which tribe claims ownership of the Takra Forest, which must be traversed to reach the Kingdom of Karaku?",
            "answer": "The Bloodfury clan"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which trio of strikers comes from 3 different countries?",
            "answer": "Messi, Suarez, Neymar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which troop type receives a boost from the Hidden Lotus decoration?",
            "answer": "Cavalry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which troop types will receive a boost from the Easter Party city theme?",
            "answer": "Archer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two animals symbolically decorated the pschent double crown worn by the Pharaohs?",
            "answer": "The cobra and vulture"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two bodies of water does the Suez Canal connect?",
            "answer": "Mediterranean Sea, Red Sea"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two cities does Portugal’s Dom Luís I Bridge connect?",
            "answer": "Porto, Vila Nova de Gaia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two English players scored in the 1966 World Cup Final between England and Germany?",
            "answer": "Martin Peters & Geoff Hurst"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two oceans does the Panama Canal connect?",
            "answer": "The Pacific and Atlantic Oceans"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two sides fought each other in the Battle of Mikatagahara?",
            "answer": "Takeda Shingen and Tokugawa Ieyasu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two teams made their World Cup debuts in 2018?",
            "answer": "Iceland & Panama"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of holy sites grant troop attack bonuses?",
            "answer": "Flame Altar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of natural disaster is measured using the Richter scale?",
            "answer": "Earthquake"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which type of stone did the ancient Egyptians extract mainly from the Nile delta?",
            "answer": "Limestone"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which unit gains a strong benefit from Sun Tzu’s “Master Strategist” skill?",
            "answer": "Infantry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which unit type does Cao Cao excel in leading?",
            "answer": "Cavalry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which unit type is strong against Archers?",
            "answer": "Cavalry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which unit type is strong against Cavalry?",
            "answer": "Infantry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which unit type is strong against Infantry?",
            "answer": "Archers"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which vitamin deficiency can cause night blindness?",
            "answer": "Vitamin A"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which war ended the rule of the House of Plantagenet and began the rule of the Tudors in England?",
            "answer": "The Wars of the Roses"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which war was fought between the British houses of Lancaster and York for the throne of England?",
            "answer": "The Wars of the Roses"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which was a lighthouse built after Macedonia conquered Egypt and was one of the seven wonders of the ancient world?",
            "answer": "The Lighthouse of Alexandria"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which was the actor Charlie Chaplin’s first ever film?",
            "answer": "Making a Living"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which were the two construction materials most heavily favored by the ancient Egyptian building industry?",
            "answer": "Mudbricks and stone"
        },
        {
            "question": "While Gutenberg introduced the printing press in Europe, his invention was influenced by which country, the first to develop a moveable type?",
            "answer": "China"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who “owns” Easter Island?",
            "answer": "Chile"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who authored the novel “No Longer Human”?",
            "answer": "Osamu Dazai"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who authored the tragedy “Medea”?",
            "answer": "Euripides"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who burned down the Epang Palace in China built during the Qin Dynasty?",
            "answer": "Xiang Yu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who came out the victor of the “Battle of Hastings”?",
            "answer": "William the Conqueror"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who came up with the Trojan Horse idea? Who won the Trojan War?",
            "answer": "Odysseus; The Greeks"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who commanded the New Model Army founded by Parliament during the English Civil War?",
            "answer": "Cromwell"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who compiled the fairytales that eventually featured in the “Grimms’ Fairy Tales”?",
            "answer": "The Brothers Grimm"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who conquered the “Kingdom of the Vandals and Alans” in the Vandalic War?",
            "answer": "Belisarius"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who created the famous sculpture “The Thinker”?",
            "answer": "Auguste Rodin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who defeated the Sphinx according to Greek legend?",
            "answer": "Oedipus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who designed the “Ottoman Cannon”?",
            "answer": "Urban"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who designed the current World Cup trophy?",
            "answer": "Silvio Gazzaniga"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who designed the Djoser, the first ancient pyramid featuring a stepped design?",
            "answer": "Imhotep"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who did Boudica lead the tribes of Britain in a revolt against?",
            "answer": "The Roman Empire"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who did France play in the quarterfinals of the 2006 World Cup in Germany?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who directed the film “Spring in a Small Town”?",
            "answer": "Fei Mu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who first implemented the Julian Calendar in Rome?",
            "answer": "Julius Caesar"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who formed the First Triumvirate with Caesar and Pompey?",
            "answer": "Crassus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded England’s Order of the Garter?",
            "answer": "Edward III"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded the “Malacca Sultanate”?",
            "answer": "Parameswara"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded the “Spanish Armada”?",
            "answer": "Philip II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded the First Persian Empire?",
            "answer": "Cyrus the Great"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded the Joseon Dynasty?",
            "answer": "Yi Seong-Gye"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded the Kamakura shogunate?",
            "answer": "Minamoto no Yoritomo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded the Kingdom of Asturias?",
            "answer": "Pelagius"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who gave the famous “I Have a Dream” speech?",
            "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
        },
        {
            "question": "Who holds the record for most goals scored in a single World Cup, at 13 goals?",
            "answer": "Just Fontaine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who initiated the first Salt March?",
            "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who invented the printing press?",
            "answer": "Johann Gutenberg"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who invented the world’s first full-sized automobile?",
            "answer": "Nicolas-Joseph Cugnot"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is considered the “Father of the Modern Olympic Games”?",
            "answer": "Pierre de Coubertin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is responsible for ushering valiant warriors into Valhalla upon death in Norse mythology?",
            "answer": "Valkyrie"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the “god of death” in ancient Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Thanatos"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the “God of War” in ancient Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Ares"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the ‘god of love’ in Norse mythology?",
            "answer": "Freyja"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the consort of the Hindu deity Vishnu?",
            "answer": "Lakshmi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the God of Sleep in ancient Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Hypnos"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the god of the sun in ancient Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Apollo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the god of thunder in Norse mythology?",
            "answer": "Thor"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the goddess of the earth in ancient Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Gaea"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the Greek goddess of night?",
            "answer": "Nyx"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the Hindu god of destruction, also known as the “Cosmic Dancer”?",
            "answer": "Shiva"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the husband of Matilda of Flanders?",
            "answer": "William I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the king of the gods in Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Zeus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the King of the Kingdom?",
            "answer": "Leader of the Alliance that conquers the Lost Temple"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the longest-serving manager in the history of Arsenal FC?",
            "answer": "Arsène Wenger"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the mortal enemy of the commander Saladin?",
            "answer": "Richard I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the mother of Cupid, the baby-faced god of love in Roman mythology?",
            "answer": "Venus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the north stand at Old Trafford named after?",
            "answer": "Sir Alex Ferguson"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the oldest player to have played in a World Cup match?",
            "answer": "Essam El Hadary"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the only manager to win the World Cup twice as a manager?",
            "answer": "Vittorio Pozzo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the only player to have played in three consecutive World Cup Finals?",
            "answer": "Cafu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the patron and protector of Athens in ancient Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Athena"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the south stand at Old Trafford named after?",
            "answer": "Sir Bobby Charlton"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the youngest player in the 2022 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Youssoufa Moukoko"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the youngest player to have played in a World Cup match?",
            "answer": "Norman Whiteside"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who killed Hector and how does Achilles die?",
            "answer": "Achilles; Arrow though his heel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who kills Odin, the king of the gods, during Ragnarok in Norse mythology?",
            "answer": "Fenrir"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who led the Kingdom of Prussia in the Seven Years’ War?",
            "answer": "Frederick II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who ordered the production of the civil manuscript popularly known as the Domesday Book?",
            "answer": "William I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who owned everything in Ancient Egyptian kingdoms?",
            "answer": "The Pharoah"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who painted “The Last Supper”?",
            "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?",
            "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who proposed the philosophical idea of “I think, therefore I am”?",
            "answer": "Descartes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who scored the famous goal known as the “hand of God”?",
            "answer": "Diego Maradona"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was believed to be the prototype of King of Hearts in poker?",
            "answer": "Charlemagne"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was called “Napoleon of crime” in some of the Sherlock Holmes stories?",
            "answer": "Professor Moriarty"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was Plato’s teacher?",
            "answer": "Socrates"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the author of the History of the Peloponnesian War?",
            "answer": "Thucydides"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the author of the novel “Lord of Rings”?",
            "answer": "J. R. R. Tolkien"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the Ceroli Chieftain that originally requested help from governors?",
            "answer": "Torgny"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the director of the game that won Game of the Year at The Game Awards 2022?",
            "answer": "Hidetaka Miyazaki"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the Emperor of the First French Empire?",
            "answer": "Napoleon Bonaparte"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the father of Edward of Woodstock?",
            "answer": "Edward III"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the father of Hannibal?",
            "answer": "Hamilcar Barca"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the father of the Frankish king Pepin the Short?",
            "answer": "Charles Martel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first astronaut to enter outer space?",
            "answer": "Yuri Gagarin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first astronomer to calculate the Roche limit?",
            "answer": "Édouard Roche"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first consul of the Roman Republic?",
            "answer": "Lucius Junius Brutus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first Emperor of Rome?",
            "answer": "Gaius Octavius Augustus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first empress regnant of the Eastern Roman Empire?",
            "answer": "Irene of Athens"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first European to reach the Cape of Good Hope?",
            "answer": "Bartolomeu Dias"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first human woman created by Hephaestus in Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Pandora"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first Italian to receive the “Pritzker Architecture Prize”?",
            "answer": "Aldo Rossi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first Japanese author to receive the Nobel Prize in Literature?",
            "answer": "Yasunari Kawabata"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first man to win the World Cup as both a captain and manager?",
            "answer": "Franz Beckenbauer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first of Henry VIII’s children to rule England?",
            "answer": "Edward VI"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first sultan of the Ayyubid Dynasty?",
            "answer": "Saladin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first woman to become a military pilot anywhere in the world?",
            "answer": "Sabiha Gökçen"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first woman to win a Nobel Prize?",
            "answer": "Marie Curie"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first World Cup mascot?",
            "answer": "World Cup Willie"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the founder of the Achaemenid Empire?",
            "answer": "Cyrus the Great"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the founder of the Edo Bakufu of Japan?",
            "answer": "Tokugawa Ieyasu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the founder of the Mongolian Empire?",
            "answer": "Genghis Khan"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the Greek and Thracian god of wine?",
            "answer": "Dionysus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the last Emperor of All Russia?",
            "answer": "Nicholas II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the last emperor of China?",
            "answer": "The Xuantong Emperor (Puyi)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the last emperor of the Holy Roman Empire?",
            "answer": "Francis II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the last female Paraoh of the Ptolemy Dynasty?",
            "answer": "Cleopatra VII"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the leader of the Western Army during the Battle of Sekigahara, which took place during Japan’s Sengoku period?",
            "answer": "Ishida Mitsunari"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the manager that led the German team to the title in the 2014 Brazil World Cup?",
            "answer": "Joachim Low"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the manager that led the West German team to the title in the 1990 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Franz Beckenbauer"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the only King of England to be executed?",
            "answer": "Charles I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the only US President that served more than 2 terms?",
            "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the top goalscorer at the 2002 World Cup held in Korea and Japan?",
            "answer": "Ronaldo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the victor in the Battle of Tours in 732 CE?",
            "answer": "Charles Martel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were the first mountaineer(s) on record to reach the summit of Mt. Everest?",
            "answer": "Tenzing Norgay and Edmund Hilary"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were the two belligerents at the Battle of Thermopylae?",
            "answer": "The Greeks and Persians"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who won the 1998 FIFA World Cup, held in France?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who won the 2019 Women’s World Cup, held in France?",
            "answer": "The United States"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who won the best young player award at the 2018 World Cup?",
            "answer": "Kylian Mbappé"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who won the first World Cup?",
            "answer": "Uruguay"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who won the Golden Ball award in the 2018 World Cup, held in Russia?",
            "answer": "Luka Modric"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote “History of Animals”?",
            "answer": "Aristotle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote “Human, All Too Human”?",
            "answer": "Nietzsche"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote “Les Miserables”?",
            "answer": "Victor Hugo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote “The Aeneid”, the first epic poem in Western literature?",
            "answer": "Virgil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote “The Symposium”?",
            "answer": "Plato"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland?",
            "answer": "Lewis Carroll"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote the “History of the Peloponnesian War”, a historical account of the titular war?",
            "answer": "Thucydides"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote The Art of War?",
            "answer": "Sun Tzu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote the opera Carmen?",
            "answer": "Georges Bizet"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote the well-known book “A Brief History of Time”?",
            "answer": "Stephen Hawking"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote the well-known book “Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind”?",
            "answer": "Yuval Noah Harari"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote the well-known science fiction series “Dune”?",
            "answer": "Frank Herbert"
        },
        {
            "question": "Whose autobiography “Living to Tell the Tale” won them the Nobel Prize in Literature?",
            "answer": "Gabriel García Márquez"
        },
        {
            "question": "Whose beauty is said to have been the cause of the Trojan War?",
            "answer": "Helen"
        },
        {
            "question": "Whose poem The Waste Land won them the Nobel Prize in Literature?",
            "answer": "T.S. Eliot"
        },
        {
            "question": "Whose victory was the orchestral work “1812 Overture” composed to commemorate?",
            "answer": "Russian Empire"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why are advantageous traits more likely to be passed onto offspring?",
            "answer": "Because they are more likely to survive and reproduce"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why do frogs and other organism produce so many eggs/offspring?",
            "answer": "The more offspring produced the more likely they will survive"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why does drinking coffee make people feel more awake?",
            "answer": "It contains caffeine"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why was British nurse Florence Nightingale known as “The Lady with the Lamp”?",
            "answer": "She would inspect patients at night"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why was scurvy once a common problem for sailors?",
            "answer": "A lack of fresh fruit and vegetables on long voyages"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why was the Dead Sea given this name?",
            "answer": "The high-saline water prevents plants and animals from thriving near it"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why were the bow and stern of Viking longboats designed to be symmetrical?",
            "answer": "To reverse direction quickly without a turn around"
        },
        {
            "question": "With which of these rulers did Queen Tamar of Georgia form a pact of non-aggression?",
            "answer": "Saladin"
        },
        {
            "question": "With whom did Minamoto no Yoshitsune raise an army to fight Taira no Kiyomori?",
            "answer": "Minamoto no Yoritomo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Without using buffs, how many Action Points can a Governor have?",
            "answer": "1,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "Work on which of these cathedrals began in Copenhagen in 1877?",
            "answer": "St. Paul’s Church"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can help your allies build/upgrade buildings, research technologies, and heal troops. But how much does each help action fill the progress bar?",
            "answer": "0.01"
        },
        {
            "question": "Zhu Geliang had no involvement in which of the following incidents recounted in the Romance of the Three Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "Yellow Turban Rebellion"
        },
        {
            "question": "Last of the Romans\" is an epithet used to describe someone With a classical Roman way of thinking. Who would NOT exemplify that?",
            "answer": "Attila"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Julius Caesar's nickname?",
            "answer": "The Uncrowned King"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these effects is NOT caused by Aethelflaed's skills?",
            "answer": "Healing slightly wounded units"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ancient Egypt, which of the following was NOT a privilege of being a 'Scribe'?",
            "answer": "Exempt from paying medical expenses if sick"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which chapter of the Kingdom Chronicles grants the Explorer for Life\" achievement if all mist is explored before the chapter's end?",
            "answer": "Long Peace"
        },
        {
            "question": "The 24 solar terms\" are a traditional Chinese calendar system used for what purpose?",
            "answer": "Agriculture"
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the word marathon\" originally refer to?",
            "answer": "A place name"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which unit gains a strong benefit from Sun Tzu's Master Strategist\" skill?",
            "answer": "Infantry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Hieroglyphs were part of which country's formal writing system?",
            "answer": "Ancient Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "By what other name is October also known under Japan's old calendar?",
            "answer": "Kannazuki"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a low country\" of Europe?",
            "answer": "The United Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following achievements must be completed before the Special Snowflake\" achievement?",
            "answer": "Long-range strike"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Pelagius' passive skills?",
            "answer": "Charge"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country did Zarathustra, of the tone poem 'Thus Spoke Zarathustra', come from?",
            "answer": "Persia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why was British nurse Florence Nightingale known as The Lady with the Lamp\"?",
            "answer": "She would inspect patients at night"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where are the world's largest proven oil reserves located?",
            "answer": "Ghawar Field"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded the Malacca Sultanate\"?",
            "answer": "Parameswara"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which modern-day city was Shakespeare's Globe Theater built in?",
            "answer": "London"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did Einstein publish his four Annus Mirabilis (Miracle Papers\")?",
            "answer": "1905"
        },
        {
            "question": "The concept of 'separation of powers' comes from which work by Montesquieu?",
            "answer": "The Spirit of Law"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT a component ingredient used to forge the Epic weapon Golden Age\"?",
            "answer": "Animal Bone"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded the Spanish Armada\"?",
            "answer": "Philip II"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who authored the tragedy Medea\"?",
            "answer": "Euripides"
        },
        {
            "question": "What can Masonry\" technology help you to improve?",
            "answer": "The building speed of buildings in your city"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these countries did NOT participate in the Northern Seven Years' War (1563-1570)?",
            "answer": "The United Kingdom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is an incorrect description of the Mare Imbrium\" on the moon?",
            "answer": "It contains a certain amount of sedimentary water"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Commander's active skill can inflict Silence?",
            "answer": "Hermann"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which theater was Beethoven's Symphony No. 5 in C Minor debuted in 1808?",
            "answer": "The Theater an der Wien"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT part of Mexico's flag?",
            "answer": "Camel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Shanghai's Jin Mao Tower has how many floors?",
            "answer": "88"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is known as The Immortal Hammer\"?",
            "answer": "Charles Martel"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the nationality of Pierre de Fermat, who proposed Fermat's Last Theorem?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT considered one of the Five Good Emperors\" of the Nerva-Antonine dynasty of ancient Rome?",
            "answer": "Commodus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Julius Caesar's skills?",
            "answer": "Military Life"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following technologies precedes Horsemanship\"?",
            "answer": "Military Discipline"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is commonly regarded as having exemplified the ideal of the Bushido Spirit\"?",
            "answer": "Kusonoki Masashige"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long did the Hundred Years' War between England and France last?",
            "answer": "116 years"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is considered one of Confucius' disciples?",
            "answer": "Yan Hui"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who designed the Ottoman Cannon\"?",
            "answer": "Urban"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which military commander was known as Teutoburg's Liberator\"?",
            "answer": "Hermann"
        },
        {
            "question": "What were the men and women hiding from on the outskirts of Florence in the novella collection The Decameron\"?",
            "answer": "The Black Plague"
        },
        {
            "question": "In DC comics, what is Batman's real name?",
            "answer": "Bruce Wayne"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is reputed to have said, I came, I saw, I conquered\"?",
            "answer": "Julius Caesar"
        },
        {
            "question": "When did the War of Austrian Succession take place?",
            "answer": "1740-1748"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT one of Cao Cao's skills?",
            "answer": "Battle of Sorrow"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which art group is known as a national treasure\" of Canada?",
            "answer": "Cirque du Soleil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote The Symposium?",
            "answer": "Plato"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote Alice's Adventures in Wonderland?",
            "answer": "Lewis Carroll"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which prominent statesman served as the first Shogun of the Edo shogunate at the end of Japan's Warring States period?",
            "answer": "Tokugawa Ieyasu"
        },
        {
            "question": "What animal is the Tigris\" named after in ancient Greek?",
            "answer": "Tiger"
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the regnal name of the last emperor of China's Qing Dynasty?",
            "answer": "Xuantong"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Matilda of Flanders' skills?",
            "answer": "Celtic Blood"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is one of Minamoto no Yoshitsune's Active Skills\"?",
            "answer": "Kyohachiryu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Whose victory was the orchestral work 1812 Overture\" composed to commemorate?",
            "answer": "Russian Empire"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the most abundant element in earth's crust?",
            "answer": "Oxygen"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following structures is a military building?",
            "answer": "Scout Camp"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is considered the Father of the Modern Olympic Games\"?",
            "answer": "Pierre de Coubertin"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the COMMANDER VIEW page, what buff do commanders acting as a Iron Guard\" get?",
            "answer": "Troop Health +1%"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, what was Achilles' only weak point?",
            "answer": "His heels"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which honorary rank was the founder of Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC) given?",
            "answer": "Colonel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who created the famous sculpture The Thinker\"?",
            "answer": "Auguste Rodin"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which nation was NOT involved in the Battle of Waterloo?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what era of Chinese history did the Battle of Fei River\" take place where a small number of soldiers conquered a vastly superior force?",
            "answer": "The Eastern Jin Dynasty"
        },
        {
            "question": "Apart from Times You Can Be Helped\" and Power\", which of the following Alliance Center parameters can also be upgraded?",
            "answer": "Reinforcement Troop Capacity"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Three Great Philosophers\" of Ancient Greece were Plato, Aristotle, and who?",
            "answer": "Socrates"
        },
        {
            "question": "Egypt's economy was primarily based on what?",
            "answer": "Agriculture"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Battle of Las Navas de Tolosa\" was a major turning point in which conflict?",
            "answer": "The Reconquista"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ancient Greek mythology, who was Hermes' father?",
            "answer": "Zeus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which artist painted the world-famous Girl with a Pearl Earring\"?",
            "answer": "Johannes Vermeer"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest animal on the planet",
            "answer": "Blue whale"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which European wrote the first travelogue detailing China's history, culture, and art?",
            "answer": "Marco Polo"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which composer wrote the opera The Ring of the Nibelung\"?",
            "answer": "Wagner"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Egyptian pharaoh's tomb did British archaeologist Howard Carter discover in 1922",
            "answer": "Tutankhamun"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of El Cid's skills?",
            "answer": "Chivalry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Belisarius' skills?",
            "answer": "Thunderous Force"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Baybar's skills?",
            "answer": "Thunderous Force"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following civilizations increases the damage of active commander skills by 5%",
            "answer": "Ottomans"
        },
        {
            "question": "Combat Tactics is an important Military Technology—what effect does it have?",
            "answer": "Increases Attack of all units"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who conquered the Kingdom of the Vandals and Alans\" in the Vandalic War?",
            "answer": "Belisarius"
        },
        {
            "question": "Machu Picchu\" is a notable relic of which civilization?",
            "answer": "The Incas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Before leading the biggest slave rebellion of Ancient Rome, what was Spartacus?",
            "answer": "Gladiator"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, the Throwing Axeman is which civilization's special unit?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Throwing Axeman is which civilization's special unit?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "What color is a polar bear's skin?",
            "answer": "Black"
        },
        {
            "question": "Darwin's last book primarily discussed which species' influence on soil?",
            "answer": "Earthworms"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was Plato's teacher?",
            "answer": "Socrates"
        },
        {
            "question": "One day\" on the planet Venus is approximately equal to how many earth days?",
            "answer": "243 days"
        },
        {
            "question": "Halley's Comet can be observed from Earth every…",
            "answer": "75-76 years"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Lohar's skills?",
            "answer": "Utter Annihilation"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following does NOT increase an Alliance's member limit?",
            "answer": "Appointing officers"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Alliance Technology Territory Guardian\" increases which attribute of troops when battling in Alliance territory?",
            "answer": "Attack"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was praised by his countrymen as Ancient Greece's best and most honest democratic representatives?",
            "answer": "Pericles"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Mulan's skills?",
            "answer": "Indomitable Army"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Beef Wellington\" involves cooking filet mignon wrapped inside which other ingredient?",
            "answer": "Puff pastry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country is not in Europe?",
            "answer": "Egypt"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many letters are used in today's version of English?",
            "answer": "26"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two cities does Portugal's Dom Luís I Bridge connect?",
            "answer": "Porto, Vila Nova de Gaia"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many items of the same quality should I equip to complete Ready for Battle\"?",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "The prehistoric humans known as homo floresiensis\" are also commonly referred to as?",
            "answer": "Hobbits"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Keira's skills?",
            "answer": "Unruly Blood"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which technology comes right before Swordsman",
            "answer": "Iron Working"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the Viking civilization's special unit?",
            "answer": "Berserker"
        },
        {
            "question": "How much does the 12-Hour Enhanced Attack item increase your troops' Attack by?",
            "answer": "5%"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many daily Activity Points do you need in Lucerne Scrolls\" to claim the Daily Gift clue reward?",
            "answer": "50"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following constetlations is shaped like a crown?",
            "answer": "Corona Borealis"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Gather Resources\" stage of the Mightiest Governor event, how many points do you get for gathering 1 Gem?",
            "answer": "150"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is nicknamed Carthage's Guardian?",
            "answer": "Hannibal Barca"
        },
        {
            "question": "Using a troop led by Julius Caesar and Cleopatra VII, which of the following actions will unlock the achievement Immortal Longings\"?",
            "answer": "Attack a city"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Grimms' fairy tale Town Musicians of Bremen\", a group of animals travels to Bremen together to become musicians. Which of the following animals is NOT in the group?",
            "answer": "Pig"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who proposed the philosophical idea of I think, therefore I am\"?",
            "answer": "Descartes"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Japan, torii\" gates are usually placed at the entrance of what buildings?",
            "answer": "Shinto shrines"
        },
        {
            "question": "Apart from Number of Scouts\" and Power\", which of the following Scout Camp parameters can also be upgraded?",
            "answer": "Scout March Speed and Exploration Range"
        },
        {
            "question": "Sandro Botticelli's painting Venus and Mars\" is famed for its vivid colors and beautiful figures. In which gallery is this painting now housed?",
            "answer": "The National Gallery in London"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the effect of the accessory Vengeance\"?",
            "answer": "Counterattack Damage +8%"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the simplified Maslow's hierarchy of needs, which need is at the top of the pyramid?",
            "answer": "Self-actualization"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ROK, which of the following is NOT one of Mulan's skills?",
            "answer": "Clever Heart"
        },
        {
            "question": "At what VIP level can you purchase a VIP Special chest that contains enough Hannibal Barca sculptures to unlock his Expertise?",
            "answer": "14"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following countries is located entirely in the Northern Hemisphere",
            "answer": "None of these answers are correct"
        },
        {
            "question": "To unlock the achievement Huarong Trail\", you must use Guan Yu to defeat a troop led by which of the following commanders?",
            "answer": "Cao Cao"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ROK, which commander is nicknamed Father of Conquest\"?",
            "answer": "Baibars"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the champion Keira's nickname?",
            "answer": "The Red Chameleon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Homer's epic The Iliad\" focuses on events happening during which war or battle?",
            "answer": "The Trojan War"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who painted The Last Supper\"?",
            "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who painted The Last Supper?",
            "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci"
        },
        {
            "question": "The city decoration Ishtar Gate\" is a tribute to which of the following civilizations?",
            "answer": "Babylonia"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the seven wonders of the world were created to cure the new Queen of Babylon's homesickness?",
            "answer": "The Hanging Gardens"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote the well-known book Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind\"?",
            "answer": "Yuval Noah Harari"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 49 BCE Roman Civil war, Who was Julius Caesar's primary opponent?",
            "answer": "Gnaeus Pompeius Magnus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these items can NOT be purchased within the Mysterious Merchant's Boutique?",
            "answer": "Passport Page"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which city-state of Ancient Greece was known for its Brutal military training and bravery",
            "answer": "Sparta"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Commander View page, what buff do commanders acting as a Ranger\" get",
            "answer": "+5% XP Gain & Damage vs. Barbarians / (none of these answers)"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, to whom did Paris, the Prince of Troy, give a golden apple inscribed with, To the most beautiful goddess\"?",
            "answer": "Aphrodite"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Peerless Scholar event, how many answers do you need to get correct in the Preliminary to qualify for the Midterm?",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "Galileo's Leaning Tower of Pisa experiment overturned a theory of which Ancient Greek scientist?",
            "answer": "Aristotle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the Hindu god of destruction, also known as the Cosmic Dancer\"?",
            "answer": "Shiva"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders was part of the Hundred Years' War?",
            "answer": "Joan of Arc"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many times is the character 1\" used when you write from number 1 to number 99",
            "answer": "20"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ROK, which commander has the title Beloved of Thoth\"?",
            "answer": "Thutmose III"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which artist designed St. Peter's Basilica in the Vatican?",
            "answer": "Michelangelo"
        },
        {
            "question": "What ingredients are used to make zongzi\", a traditional food eaten in China during the Dragon Boat Festival?",
            "answer": "Glutinous rice"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the world's oldest film festival?",
            "answer": "Venice Film Festival"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these films won the Golden Lion at the 2004 Venice Film Festival?",
            "answer": "Vera Drake"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these characters is from Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Seas\"?",
            "answer": "Captain Nemo"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ROK, which commander has the nickname Queen of Sicily\"?",
            "answer": "Constance"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is the world's largest island",
            "answer": "Greenland"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Shakespeare's Macbeth, the titular character murders King Duncan of Scotland. What is the name of Duncan's eldest son?",
            "answer": "Malcolm"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the alternative name of Shakespeare's play Twelfth Night?",
            "answer": "What You Will"
        },
        {
            "question": "At What level does the Trading Post's transport tax rate become 10%?",
            "answer": "24"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ROK, which of Sun Tzu's Skills is enhanced by his expertise skill?",
            "answer": "Art of War"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which French monarch was known as Saint Louis\"?",
            "answer": "Louis IX"
        },
        {
            "question": "The kingdom title 'Queen' increases which of the following?",
            "answer": "Gathering Speed"
        },
        {
            "question": "Ru ware\" is one of the most famous types of Chinese pottery, known for its delicate pale blue glaze. Which dynasty did it originate from?",
            "answer": "Song"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many minutes' worth total of speedups can be obtained from purchasing the 7-Day Speedup Supply\" in addition to the immediate 1,050 Gem reward?",
            "answer": "3,150 minutes"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ark of Osiris which speedup can be used?",
            "answer": "Healing Speed Up"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which formation is the Imperial War Drum\" armament for?",
            "answer": "V"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following civilizations gives a 5% attack bonus to cavalry units?",
            "answer": "Germany"
        },
        {
            "question": "To whom did India give the title Mahatma\"?",
            "answer": "Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who gave the famous I Have a Dream\" speech?",
            "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
        },
        {
            "question": "What's the primary cause of the formation of the Himalayas?",
            "answer": "Collision between plates"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following commanders' sculptures cannot be donated to the Past Glory\" event after the Lost Kingdom has been opened?",
            "answer": "Aethelflaed"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country won the highest number of world cups?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a light-year\" a measure of?",
            "answer": "Distance"
        },
        {
            "question": "On which ingredient was the 1986 Mexico World Cup's mascot based on?",
            "answer": "Pepper"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is considered to be the seminal work of the French playwright Moliére?",
            "answer": "Tartuffe"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Hermann's skills?",
            "answer": "Irresistible"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is most likely to have directly led to the bronze age?",
            "answer": "Bronze is harder and more durable than other metals available at the time"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Lohar's Trial event, how can players obtain Bone Necklaces?",
            "answer": "Defeating ordinary Barbarians"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is Commander Hannibal Barca good at?",
            "answer": "Attacking cities"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following items can be used to upgrade a commander's skills?",
            "answer": "Commander Sculptures"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders' Expertise Skill is the enhanced version of an existing skill?",
            "answer": "Bjorn Ironside"
        },
        {
            "question": "When a governor's city hall reaches level 25, how many farms can they build?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Many well-known figures fought in the Third Crusade. Which of these leaders died during this crusade?",
            "answer": "Frederick Barbarossa"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ROK, What is the prerequisite technology for the Herbal Medicine military technology?",
            "answer": "Camouflage"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following methods will NOT increase your academy's research speed?",
            "answer": "Justice Title"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Futhark rune represents Tyr, the god of war and justice in Germanic mythology?",
            "answer": "Tiwaz"
        },
        {
            "question": "When sailing through a thunderstorm, one can occasionally see a lightning\" effect at the tip of the mast. What is this phenomenon called?",
            "answer": "Saint Elmo's Fire"
        },
        {
            "question": " Which of these commanders will gain a bonus from the Museum Relic Twin Dragons Inscription\"?",
            "answer": "Yi Seong-Gye"
        },
        {
            "question": "In ROK, What do you have to do to complete the quest Sword of the King\"?",
            "answer": "Recruit 200 infantry units"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following stories is not included in One Thousand and One Nights\"?",
            "answer": "Layla and Majnun"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these following methods will NOT increase your academy's research speed?",
            "answer": "Becoming your kingdom's Justice"
        },
        {
            "question": "What two countries together made up the Iberian Union\"?",
            "answer": "Portugal and Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "The four biggest musicals in the world are Cats, Les Misérables, Miss Saigon, and...",
            "answer": "The Phantom of the Opera"
        },
        {
            "question": "The four biggest musicals in the world are Cats, Les Miserables, Miss Saigon, and...",
            "answer": "The Phantom of the Opera"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is the world's first national park?",
            "answer": "Yellowstone National Park"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the last female Pharaoh of the Ptolemy Dynasty?",
            "answer": "Cleopatra VII"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which country was the famed revolutionary and military strategist Simon Bolivar born?",
            "answer": "Venezuela"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which military leader was known as the Reformer of the Legions\"?",
            "answer": "Gaius Marius"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's does the Skillful Craftsman\" alliance skill do when used?",
            "answer": "Greatly increases alliance flag construction speed"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the Skillful Craftsman\" alliance skill do when used?",
            "answer": "Greatly increases alliance flag construction speed"
        },
        {
            "question": "The saying The Empire on which the sun never sets\" was originally used in reference to which country's empire?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "Albert Einstein was awarded the 1921 Nobel Prize in Physics for which discovery?",
            "answer": "Photoelectric effect"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is one of Diaochan's Active Skills?",
            "answer": "Dance of Chaos"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Renaissance was a rebirth\" of what?",
            "answer": "Classical culture"
        },
        {
            "question": "Widely regarded as the first ever science fiction movie, A Trip to the Moon was the work of which French director?",
            "answer": "Georges Melies"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country's explorers were the first to land in Antarctica?",
            "answer": "Norway"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these events marks the beginning of Roman rule over Greece?",
            "answer": "Battle of Corinth"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which poet wrote Theogony\", which describes the origins and genealogy of the Greek gods?",
            "answer": "Hesiod"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the Parthenon dedicated to?",
            "answer": "Athena"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Greek mythology, what was the name of Hades' 3-headed dog which guarded the gates of the Underworld?",
            "answer": "Cerberus"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, the Cataphract is which civilization's special unit?",
            "answer": "Byzantium"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Homer's epic The Iliad\", which of the following goddesses was NOT part of the competition for the Golden Apple?",
            "answer": "Eris"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which gas makes up more than 90% of Mars' atmosphere?",
            "answer": "Carbon Dioxide"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the major greenhouse gases in earth's atmosphere?",
            "answer": "Nitrogen"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient civilization built the Lost City\" of Machu Picchu?",
            "answer": "The Incas"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is China's earliest known book of military strategy?",
            "answer": "Sun Tzu's The Art of War\""
        },
        {
            "question": "Advantages of Johannes Gutenberg's printing press include all of the following except what?",
            "answer": "Increase in church power"
        },
        {
            "question": "A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm.\" Which of Isaac Asimov's Three Laws of Robotics is this?",
            "answer": "First law"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first of Henry VIII's children to rule England?",
            "answer": "Edward VI"
        },
        {
            "question": "For equipment with special talent bonuses, how much will their attributes be enhanced by when equipped by a commander with the corresponding talent?",
            "answer": "30%"
        },
        {
            "question": "Of the below commanders, which is best suited to lead troops AGAINST cavalry enemies",
            "answer": "Sun Tzu"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which region in Italy is the Cathedral of Santa Maria del Fiore located?",
            "answer": "Tuscany"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long does the Basic Army Expansion\" boost last?",
            "answer": "4h"
        },
        {
            "question": "In RoK, the Hwarang is which civilization's special unit?",
            "answer": "Korea"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these ancient Greek philosophers did NOT participate in the discussion on justice in Plato's Republic?",
            "answer": "Protagoras"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT Zeus' child in Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Hera"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is Zeus' elder brother in Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Poseidon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Where did Hippocrates, the Father of Medicine\", come from?",
            "answer": "Greece"
        },
        {
            "question": "In Ancient Greece, which philosopher liked to discuss ideas on a street which then got the nickname Peripatetic School\"?",
            "answer": "Aristotle"
        },
        {
            "question": "Commander Bjorn Ironside's Viking Lord\" skill benefits which of the following unit types?",
            "answer": "Infantry"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these ancient Greek writers is regarded as the father of comedy\"?",
            "answer": "Aristophanes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the god of death\" in ancient Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Thanatos"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which city-state defeated Sparta in the Battle of Leuctra\"?",
            "answer": "Thebes"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the COMMANDER VIEW page, what buff do commanders acting as a Tax Officer\" get?",
            "answer": "Gathering Speed +5%"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who authored the novel No Longer Human\"?",
            "answer": "Osamu Dazai"
        },
        {
            "question": "The auction house Sotheby's was founded in 1744 in which English city?",
            "answer": "London"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Aral Sea was once the world's fourth largest lake, but since then it has mostly dried up. Where is it located?",
            "answer": "Central Asia"
        },
        {
            "question": "During China's Warring States Period, which state defeated the other six and built the unified Chinese empire?",
            "answer": "Qin"
        },
        {
            "question": "What's does the Nature's Gift\" alliance skill do when used",
            "answer": "Summon resource point in a selected area (cannot be used in the lost kingdom)"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the Nature's Gift\" alliance skill do when used",
            "answer": "Summon resource point in a selected area (cannot be used in the lost kingdom)"
        },
        {
            "question": "In China's Han Dynasty, who opened the Silk Road on the orders of Emperor Wu?",
            "answer": "Zhang Qian"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is an incorrect description of the Battle of Poitiers\"?",
            "answer": "The campaign took place during World War I"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is an incorrect description of wind energy",
            "answer": "It is not a form of renewable energy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the first Italian to receive the Pritzker Architecture Prize\"?",
            "answer": "Aldo Rossi"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which emperor was named the Khan of Heaven\" by various Turkic nomads during the Sui and Tang dynasties?",
            "answer": "Emperor Taizong of Tang"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what country did the Battle of Marengo\" take place?",
            "answer": "Italy"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which artist is buried at the Pantheon?",
            "answer": "Raphael"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which musician composed The Marriage of Figaro\"?",
            "answer": "Mozart"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Day of the Tiles\" is regarded by some historians to mark the beginning of the French Revolution. In what city did it take place?",
            "answer": "Grenoble"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these works of Japanese Monogatari literature describes the legend of Kaguya-hime\"?",
            "answer": "The Tale of The Bamboo Cutter"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these countries is NOT a founding member of NATO (in 1949)?",
            "answer": "Turkey"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote the well-known book A Brief History of Time\"?",
            "answer": "Stephen Hawking"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is the God of War\" in ancient Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Ares"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which demigod captures Cerberus, the three-headed hound of Hades\", according to Greek mythology?",
            "answer": "Hercules"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who wrote Human, All Too Human\"?",
            "answer": "Nietzsche"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who owns\" Easter Island?",
            "answer": "Chile"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Dragonfly Cutter\" was the weapon of choice of which legendary warrior?",
            "answer": "Honda Tadakatsu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who came out the victor of the Battle of Hastings\"?",
            "answer": "William the Conqueror"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is nicknamed Bow of Revolution\"?",
            "answer": "Yi Seong-Gye"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following juice is contained in the classic cocktail Bloody Mary\"?",
            "answer": "Tomato Juice"
        },
        {
            "question": "The process of splitting atoms is known as what?",
            "answer": "Fission"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is considered an energy source?",
            "answer": "Petroleum"
        },
        {
            "question": "Raphael is best known for?",
            "answer": "School of Athens"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many fingers does the cartoon character mickey mouse have on each hand?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "The end justifies the means\" was a key belief of the author of The Prince\". What was his name?",
            "answer": "Machiavelli"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Windsor knot\" was made popular by which king of England?",
            "answer": "Edward VIII"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which ancient Greek scholar laid the foundations for future European mathematics and authored the Elements\" of geometry?",
            "answer": "Euclid"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following does the green Olympic Ring represent?",
            "answer": "Oceania"
        },
        {
            "question": "Mutations are a change in what?",
            "answer": "DNA"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a nonrenewable energy source?",
            "answer": "Water"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a name for sedimentary rock formed from decayed plant materiel in swampy areas?",
            "answer": "Coal"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a nonrenewable energy source (such as coal, oil, or natural gas)?",
            "answer": "Fossil Fuel"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the renewable energy derived from burning organic materials such as wood and alcohol?",
            "answer": "Biomass energy"
        },
        {
            "question": "First general of the Edo shogunate?",
            "answer": "Tokugawa Ieyasu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a term for a valuable material of geologic origin that can be extracted from the earth?",
            "answer": "Natural Resources"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were the first mountaineer(s) on record to reach the summit of Mt.Everest?",
            "answer": "Tenzing Norgay and Edmund Hilary"
        },
        {
            "question": "The American Dream\" is rooted in which of these documents?",
            "answer": "The Declaration of Independence"
        },
        {
            "question": "The Independence March\" is the national anthem of which country?",
            "answer": "Turkey"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which English palace did the Star Chamber\" sit?",
            "answer": "Palace of Westminster"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year was the first edition of The Diary of Anne Frank\" published?",
            "answer": "1947"
        },
        {
            "question": "The El Nino\" phenomenon is named after which of these festivals?",
            "answer": "Christmas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Tongwancheng\" was the capital of which ethnic group from ancient China?",
            "answer": "The Xiongnu"
        },
        {
            "question": "To which army did the Varangian Guard\" belong?",
            "answer": "The Byzantine army"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many World Cup titles has Pele won?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "Keira once defied the world's expectations about her in a glorious battle. Where did this battle take place?",
            "answer": "Sunset Canyon"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who won the 2019 Women's World Cup, held in France?",
            "answer": "The United States"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who did France play in the quarter finals of the 2006 World Cup in Germany?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year was the World Cup first televised?",
            "answer": "1954"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the 2002 World Cup, which goalkeeper saved two penalty kicks during regular play?",
            "answer": "Brad Friedel"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the only country to have won both the Men's and Women's World Cup?",
            "answer": "Germany"
        },
        {
            "question": "According to FIFA which was the earlier form of football?",
            "answer": "Cuju"
        },
        {
            "question": "Eng is the FIFA code of which country?",
            "answer": "England"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which player scored more number of goals in FIFA World Cup?",
            "answer": "Miroslav Klose"
        },
        {
            "question": "In 1998, the 16th FIFA World Cup was held in which country?",
            "answer": "France"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following players will be playing in the 2022 World Cup without an active club contract?",
            "answer": "Cristiano Ronaldo"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many World Cup titles Italy won?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which inventor built the world's first electric locomotive in 1837?",
            "answer": "Robert Davidson"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who invented the world's first full-sized automobile?",
            "answer": "Nicolas-Joseph Cugnot"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which city was the world's first international soccer match held?",
            "answer": "Glasgow"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the largest pyramid in the world?",
            "answer": "The Great Pyramid of Cholula"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these women is NOT considered one of the 'Four Beauties' of ancient China?",
            "answer": "Bao Si"
        },
        {
            "question": "Diego Velazquez, the painter of the realist work Portrait of Pope Innocent X, was from which country?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "Li Xin, the ancestor of the Flying General\" Li Guang, was a general of which state during the Warring States period of Chinese history?",
            "answer": "Qin"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year was equestrianism first included as an Olympic sport?",
            "answer": "1900 Paris Olympics"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Chinese ethnic groups is known for drinking kumis, a drink made from fermented mare's milk?",
            "answer": "Mongols"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which flavor of soup can does NOT appear in Andy Warhol's famous work titled Campbell's Soup Cans\"?",
            "answer": "Corn"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was NOT essential for a Vizier, the Pharaoh's most senior civil servant, in ancient Egypt?",
            "answer": "To have royal blood"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander has a crown with gemstones of a different color to the others'?",
            "answer": "Queen Tamar of Georgia"
        },
        {
            "question": "When did the hard-boiled\" or noir\" literary genre of fiction first fluorish?",
            "answer": "1920s"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which commander is known as Kamakura's Warlord?",
            "answer": "Minamoto no Yoshitsune"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many Legendary Commander Sculptures are awarded to the top finisher by total rankings in the The Mightiest Governor\" event?",
            "answer": "180"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the color of the floral headdress worn by commander Sarka in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "Red"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what city did Henri I de Bourbon, Prince of Conde, pass away?",
            "answer": "Saint-Jean-d'Angely"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country is famously associated with tandoori chicken, a chicken dish marinated with yoghurt and spices?",
            "answer": "India"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these terrain types exerts a slight penalty on troop Defense on the Treasure Hill map in Champions of Olympia\"?",
            "answer": "Whirlwind"
        },
        {
            "question": "Into what shape does commander Yi Seong-Gye's fan-shaped active skill transform after gaining Expertise?",
            "answer": "A circle"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many bowmen are shown practicing in the Archery Range when training composite bowmen?",
            "answer": "6"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which sculpture was once described by Mark Twain as the \"the most mournful and moving piece of stone in the world\"?",
            "answer": "The Lion of Lucerne"
        },
        {
            "question": "How long does the rune dropped by defeating the Guardian remain on the map?",
            "answer": "8 hours"
        },
        {
            "question": "ow much capacity does a Lvl 15 Hospital provide (excluding boosts)?",
            "answer": "29,000"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these items may be selected from the Lvl 3 \"Pick One\" Resource Chest?",
            "answer": "150,000 Food"
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the name for ancient Egypt's Luxor Temple also mean?",
            "answer": "The southern sanctuary"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many points are gained per Lvl 3 unit severely wounded/killed in the \"Stage 5: Enemy Elimination\" segment of the \"Mightiest Governor\" event?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these Blessings immediately inflicts a 10% loss of troop power on your enemy at the start of battle in the \"Golden Kingdom\" event?",
            "answer": "Anchor"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which city in the United States has McDonald's established a Hamburger University?",
            "answer": "Chicago"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders has also been called a \"Holy Overlord\"?",
            "answer": "El Cid"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many points are earned per 1 point of upgraded Power within the \"Stage 4: Power Upgrade\" segment of \"The Mightiest Governor\" event?",
            "answer": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these is NOT a type of Japanese wagyu?",
            "answer": "Ronguhon Wagyu"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many beasts can you expect to see fighting alongside Lvl 20 barbarian troops in Rise of Kingdoms?",
            "answer": "1 bear and 2 wolves"
        },
        {
            "question": "What letter is shown on the Scolas' Lucky Coin decoration?",
            "answer": "L"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many patrolling soldiers roam a governor's walls?",
            "answer": "7"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these commanders does NOT carry a shield",
            "answer": "Charlemagne"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many \"Golden Kingdom Equipment Troves\" are contained within the Golden Chest earned from stage 16 of the \"Golden Kingdom\" event?",
            "answer": "3"
        },
        {
            "question": "The coffee bean is in fact a type of...?",
            "answer": "Fruit"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the minimum number of Silver Keys that can be obtained from the \"Treasure of Wisdom\" bundle?",
            "answer": "2"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what climate does basil, known in Europe as the \"King of Herbs\", largely grow?",
            "answer": "Tropical areas"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which commander's background picture can you see a dog?",
            "answer": "Richard I"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which commander's background picture can you see a chicken?",
            "answer": "Queen Tamar of Georgia"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which commander's background picture can you see a sakura tree?",
            "answer": "Minamoto no Yoshitsune"
        },
        {
            "question": "What caused the deaths of Ceroli Chieftain Dekar's parents?",
            "answer": "The discovery of their witchcraft studies"
        },
        {
            "question": "Along with Henri Matisse, which of these artists is considered one of the founders of the Fauvism movement?",
            "answer": "Andre Derain"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Byzantine empress, considered by some scholars to be an empress regnant, ruled as regent for her son while he was still a child?",
            "answer": "Theodora"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which continent is the bitter melon native to?",
            "answer": "Africa"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which kingdom did London belong to during the Anglo-Saxon Heptarchy period?",
            "answer": "Kingdom of Essex"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who masterminded the assassination of Julius Caesar?",
            "answer": "Gaius Cassius Longinus"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which was the only ancient civilization to develop in a tropical jungle rather than a river basin?",
            "answer": "The Incas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which county was allowed to keep the Jules Rimet Trophy permanently?",
            "answer": "Brazil"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which European country's king funded Christopher Columbus' famous expedition?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many pieces of Normal iron ore must be combined to make a piece of Advanced iron ore?",
            "answer": "4"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the COMMANDER VIEW page, what buff do commanders acting as a \"Drillmaster\" get?",
            "answer": "+1% Troop Attack"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these was the world's first space station?",
            "answer": "Salyut"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these research stations is at the highest latitude?",
            "answer": "Amundsen-Scott South Pole Station"
        },
        {
            "question": "hat is Luka Modric's jersey number on Real Madrid?",
            "answer": "10"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many points are there on a standard Go board?",
            "answer": "19x19"
        },
        {
            "question": "In \"Crime and Punishment\", what is the job of the first person Raskolnikov murders?",
            "answer": "Pawnbroker"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Chinese poet penned the poem \"Li Sao\"?",
            "answer": "Qu Yuan"
        },
        {
            "question": "Bangkok is the capital of which country?",
            "answer": "Thailand"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which is the world's smallest island country?",
            "answer": "Nauru"
        },
        {
            "question": "Held in 1929, how long did the first Academy Awards (\"Oscars\") ceremony take?",
            "answer": "15 minutes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these countries was NOT a founding member of NATO (in 1949)",
            "answer": "Turkey"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the southern most point of Africa?",
            "answer": "Cape Agulhas"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which German psychologist discovered the human brain's forgetting curve?",
            "answer": "Hermann Ebbinghaus"
        },
        {
            "question": "During which emperor's reign was the Roman Colosseum completed?",
            "answer": "Titus"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the Mightiest Governor event, what is the minimum ranking you need to achieve to receive 10 event commander sculptures?",
            "answer": "15th"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country is Catalhoyuk located in?",
            "answer": "Turkey"
        },
        {
            "question": "The epic \"Poem of EI Cid\" originated from which country?",
            "answer": "Spain"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of Queen Tamar of Georgia's skills is enhanced by her skill \"Glory of Faith\"?",
            "answer": "Ode to Freedom"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of these artworks is not by Leonardo da Vinci?",
            "answer": "The School of Athens"
        },
        {
            "question": "What nationality was Miguel de Cervantes, author of \"Don Quixote\"?",
            "answer": "Spanish"
        },
        {
            "question": "In which sea did the Battle of Actium take place?",
            "answer": "Ionian Sea"
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did chemists first discover the presence of magnesium in chlorophyll?",
            "answer": "1906"
        },
        {
            "question": " Which of these is NOT one of the Winning Stratagems listed in theancient Chinese military textbook, the \"Thirty-Six Stratagems\"?",
            "answer": "The \"empty fort\" strategy"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the word \"Formula\" in \"Formula 1 Racing\" refer to?",
            "answer": "The rules which participating cars must follow"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following characters are NOT present in the \"Journey to the West\" story?",
            "answer": "Third Sister Hu"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which philosopher wrote \"Utopia\"?",
            "answer": "Plato"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which famous Japanese samurai was called \"Ushiwakamaru\" as a child?",
            "answer": "Minamoto no Yoshitsune"
        },
        {
            "question": "Who directed the film Spring in a Small Town?",
            "answer": "fei mu"
        }
    ]
}
